All right.
I've told you a little bit about
what MongoDB is, and now
I want to show you end to and
how we're going to build an
application using Java.
So over here we have MongoDB.
And MongoDB on your computer
is going to
start a MongoDB process.
So that's going to be
the process that
actually runs MongoDB.
There's a couple different
ways to connect.
One of things I'm going to show
you is the Mongo shell.
The Mongo shell is a standalone
program called
Mongo that has a JavaScript
shell language built inside it
and connects via
TCP to MongoDB.
And this is a way to manipulate
data and inspect data.
But in this class, we're going
to build Java applications.
So we're going to
build a blog.
And the blog is going to have a
bunch of pages for inserting
posts, and showing posts, and
inserting comments, and
showing comments.
So this is the blog.
And this is all going
to written in Java.
So this is a Java application.
And there's several different
parts of this.
There's our application
code itself.
I'll call that our code.
And our Java code is going to
use two different frameworks
that are going to make it easier
to write web apps.
One is called Spark Java.
And the other one is
called Free Marker.
So Spark Java is a micro web
framework inspired by Sinatra
that will allow us to easily set
up routes that map to URLs
so that when a request comes
in for a particular URL, we
can handle it and we can make
a response via HTTP.
So that's what Spark
Java does.
And then Free Marker is a
templating language that
allows us to create HTML views
so that we can use Model View
Controller type programming,
where the view, which is the
UI part, is separate from the
controller, which handles user
input in the model, which is
the underlying logic of the
application.
Now, this all runs inside JVM,
because this is Java.
So it's all running
inside this JVM.
Now, all this code in order to
talk to MongoDB, needs to talk
to the Mongo Java driver.
And the Mongo Java driver is a
library that's going to be
linked in and that is actually
going to be the part that is
making the TCP connections
to MongoDB for you.
So you're going to write
some Java code.
It's going to use Spark Java,
which we'll go over.
And Free Marker, which will go
over, which is a templating
language and then also uses the
Mongo Java driver, which
is Java code meant to talk to
MongoDB and retrieve data and
insert data to the database.
And all of this together is
going to present this blog.
And then the user is on
the other side in
their house or something.
And this user is talking
to this process.
Normally for a web request,
it would be port 80.
But in this class, we're often
going to use 8082 because 80
is reserved, and a little
difficult to use that port if
you're not root on
the computer.
And then this might go through
some sort of network address
translation through a Linksys
box or something like that.
So in this class, we're going
to give you most of the code
for the blog.
And you're just going to make
fairly small modifications so
that you can manipulate data in
the database, because the
point of this course is not to
teach you how to be a web
programmer.
It's really to teach you
how to use MongoDB.
And so the motivating example
for some of the
work is this blog.
But we don't expect you to be
able to create this whole
thing from scratch
for this course.
So that's the end to end view
of what an application might
look like using Java.
So you have Java code that's
compiled into bytecode that
runs in the JVM and then also
hooks into the Mongo driver
for Java and also in our case,
uses the Spark Java framework
and the Free Marker templating
language to make the whole
thing create a web app that
is presented to the
user on port 8082.
Now that we know how this all
works, let's now look at the
Mongo shell, this part right
here, to see how we might add
a little bit of data or retrieve
a little bit of data
from MongoDB.