All right, now, it is time to learn how to install MongoDB.
Now, I'm going to show you how to install it on a Mac, and
then in a separate video segment, Dwight Merriman, is
going to show you how to install it on a PC in Windows.
And that's a video segment from our M102 class.
So let's get started.
The first thing I need to do is find MongoDB, and typically
the way you would do that on the web is you would type
"download MongoDB" into Google, and then it would
bring you a bunch of links.
And in this case, I'm going to go for the first organic
search result, which is at mongodb.org, and that's going
to bring us to this page.
So on this page, you're going to see, along the top, a bunch
of different platforms for which we build MongoDB, and
then on the left here, in this column,
are different releases.
So the one that you want to use is the top one, and that's
going to be our most recent stable release.
Now, the second digit here it tells you whether or not it's
a stable release or not.
If it's an even digit, like 2.4, it's a stable release.
And the last part, which is 0.5, is which maintenance
revision it is.
So in this case, it's the fifth revision,
and it's a 2.4 release.
And then over here on the bottom, there are other
releases that I won't go through right now.
So we're on a Mac, so we're going to pull down a 64-bit
release, and the Mac OS is 64-bit operating system.
On some operating systems, you can get a 32-bit release,
which we don't recommend unless you really need it
because MongoDB uses memory map files.
And using a 32-bit release will limit your files to two
gigabytes, so it'll limit your collections to two gigabytes.
Let's download this 64-bit version for Mac OS, and you
can see it's downloading here on the bottom.
It's about 80-something megabytes, and this is a
pretty fast connection we have here in the building, so we're
already done.
Let's bring up a terminal window on a Mac, and from
there, I'm going to go into the download directory, tilde
downloads directory, and see what's there.
And you can see that we have the tarball that we just
downloaded from the internet.
And I'm going to, now, expand that tarball using the tar xvf
command, and on a Mac, you can also double-click on this in
the finder.
I think it'll work as well.
And then that's going to expand it into a bunch of
different directories, ls, see what directories are there.
I'm going to cd into the directory, ls again.
I see that there's a license, a
readme, and the bin directory.
Bin directory's really the interesting one.
It has a bunch of executables that are related to MongoDB,
and the ones we're going to focus on right now are the
mongod executable, which runs the server process itself, and
the mongo executable, which is the shell that will connect to
that process.
Now, in order to run MongoDB, you need to have the right
directories set up so that it can store the data files away,
and by default, it puts files in the slash
Data slash DB directory.
So on a Mac, in order to write that directory, which is in
Root, I'm going to need to become Root, because that is
owned by Root.
So I'm going to do that right now.
I previously typed the password, so it didn't prompt
me for the password.
Now, I am Root, and then I'm going to use the mkdir command
to create a slash Data directory and another mkdir
command to create a slash Data slash DB directory.
And now, the final thing I'm going to do is I'm going to
use chmod to make that directory world writable so
that I can run the mongod executable as myself.
And I'm going to do that, and then I'll go into slash Data,
and then here, I'll show you the DB directory.
I use the -ld flag for ls to be able to look at a directory
versus search inside it, and you can see, it's a directory.
A DB directory is a directory that's owned by Root, but is
world writable.
Now, having the directory be world writable is probably not
a good idea for production, but for development, it's
fine, so we're going to do that.
I've now exited, so I'm now 10gen user
again on this computer.
And now I'm going to go back into my downloads directory,
and I'm going to go back into the expanded directory and
back into the bin directory, and I'm going to look there in
that directory again.
You can see I've got a bunch of executables, and I'm going
to start up the mongod daemon, and I'm going to do that by
typing dot slash mongod.
Tells the operating system to search inside the current
directory in case there's any other instance of a running
anywhere in the computer.
And if I do that, you can see it's going to print out a
bunch of stuff to the console.
This is the log for mongod, and the first thing it tells
us is that starting it up.
It's giving us the pid that it's running under, telling us
it's listening on the standard TCP port of 27017, and that
it's putting its data in slash Data slash DB, which is what
we just created.
And it gives us a limit, telling us that our rlimits
are set too low for production.
You'd want to increase those for production so that you
wouldn't have any issue with the number of connections and
number of file descriptors that the operating system
supports, but in development, this is going
to be fine for us.
Now that mongod is running, I want to make sure it's
running, so I want to run the Mongo shell.
So I'm going to do that.
I'm going to go back into the downloads directory and back
into that expanded directory, back into the bin directory,
and then I'm going to run the Mongo shell by typing dot
slash mongo.
Notice not dot slash mongo, but dot slash mongo.
And if I do that, it's going to connect, and it's going to
tell me that it's connected to the database.
It's going to give me that warning
about soft limits again.
And now connect it to the test database, and I want to put my
first document in the database.
Let's see, db.people, and I'm going to use an Insert
command, and this document's a pretty simple document.
It's going to have one key called Name with a value of
Andrew, and I'm going to insert that in the shell
return, so it seems to all be good and inserted.
And now, I'm going to try to find the document that I just
created to give myself some confidence that it really
happened, and if I do that, then I can see the document
that I just put the database, which has underscore ID
assigned by the server.
And then over here, there's my name as in the key
for the Name key.
So at this point we have MongoDB installed in the Mac.
We have MongoDB running, and we're running the Mongo shell,
and we're connecting to it.
So MongoDB is now installed on this Mac.