So in the last lesson, we
learned how to use Maven and
write a simple Hello World app
and run it from Maven on the
command line and also load a
Maven project into IntelliJ
and run from IntelliJ.
So the next step is
to bring Mongo in.
So in order to use Mongo from a
job application, we need the
Mongo Java driver.
So this is going to be our first
exposure to that driver.
So the first thing
we need to do,
obviously, is get the driver.
And we're going to use
Maven to do this.
So I have a commented out piece
here, and I'm going to
uncomment and add a dependency
on the Java driver.
So it looks like this.
The group ID is org.mongodb,
the artifact ID is
mongo-java-driver, and the
version we'll be using in this
class, which is the latest
production release, is 2.10.1.
You can see that IntelliJ
automatically added this Mongo
Java driver to the
external library.
So let's start a new class--
Hello World MongoDB style.
And we'll add a main.
And now what we're going to do
in this class is just do the
simplest thing that I can think
of, which is to find a
single document from a
collection that's already
existing in the database.
So I created this collection
earlier.
And it's in the course
database.
And there's a collection
called Hello.
And there's a single document
there with a named property
equal to MongoDB.
So in my job application, the
way this works is I create an
instance of MongoClient, which
is the entry point into a
Mongo cluster-- in this
case, a single
stand-alone instance of Mongo.
I'll create a new instance of
MongoClient, which can throw
unknown host exceptions, so we
have to catch that or throw it
from our method.
So you can see that we added
two imports-- one is
com.mongodb.MongoClient
and the other is just
java.net.unknownhostexception.
So this, by default, connects
to local host port 27017,
which happens to be the default
for MongoD, as well.
We can be explicit about it by
saying local host or local
host 27017 or use the server
address class and put that
same information here.
So now we have a client, which
is basically a logical
connection to a Mongo cluster.
And we need to get a database.
So the database class in
the Java driver is
called DB, all caps.
So I'll create an
instance of--
actually, I won't create
an instance.
I'll get an instance
from the client.
The database is called Course.
And then from the database we
get a collection, and that
class in the Java driver
is called DBCollection.
And we get that from the
database, like this.
And the final thing we want
to do is the findOne.
And that looks like this.
We just say collection.findOne.
And what's the return
type of findOne?
Well, it's a DB object.
So I'm going to store this in
an instance of DB object.
And the last thing I'll
do is print it out.
I can run it from here.
I removed JUnit from the POM,
so I'm going to just remove
this class.
And it prints out the document
in JSON format.
And we can also run this
from here, as well.
So this class is called--
copy the reference and I'm going
to change the main class
to Hello World MongoDB style,
and I'll run it.
And, the same thing--
it prints out the document.
So that's Hello World
Mongo style.
And we can see that we created
a Mongo client to connect to
the server running on local host
27017, opened the course
database and then the Hello
collection, and did a findOne,
and printed it out.