We've seen our web application
framework, Spark,
but there's a problem.
So you see here, where were
returning Hello World from
Spark, that's fine.
Spark will call to string
on that and return
that as the web page.
But we want to put a fair amount
of HTML in there, and
it's not going to be very pretty
if we just embed HTML
in a big string to return
from the handle method.
So we need some sort of
templating library to use.
And again, there's a lot of
templating libraries.
But a simple one to use with
Spark is one called
FreeMarker.
Now FreeMarker has been around
for quite awhile.
It's just a template engine.
As it says, it's a generic tool
to generate text output,
anything from HTML to source
code, based on templates.
The basic idea with it is, you
define templates files with
the .ftl extension.
And they have place holders,
like, in this case, $ curly
brace, name, curly brace.
And at run time you combine the
template file with a Java
map, typically, which
has keys and values.
And the FreeMarker processor
combines the map with the
template file and
produces output.
So in this case, it'll replace
$ curly brace name with the
name property of the data
map, which is Fred.
So let's go and write
some code.
The first thing we need
is a dependency.
So I have this commented
out here.
I'll uncomment the dependency on
FreeMarker in the palm.xml.
The group ID is org.freemarker.
The artifact is freemarker,
and the version is 2.3.19.
So let's create a new
application, it will be
HelloWorldFreemarkerstyle,
and start writing
some FreeMarker code.
So you have to bootstrap
yourself.
And you do that with a class
called Configuration, which is
in the package
FreeMarker.template.
So I'm going to create
a new configuration.
And I don't need to do much with
it, but one thing I do
need to do is set the class
for template loading.
So this is basically to tell the
FreeMarker configuration
how to find the FreeMarker
template.
So we're going to put our
FreeMarker templates in the
class path.
So we're going to load the
FreeMarker template in the
class path relative
to the Hello World
FreeMarker style class.
And we'll say that
it's in slash.
So we should look at the start
of the class path.
So I defined a template
already.
So I created a resources
directory which Maven and
IntelliJ already knows to
include in the class path.
And there's a simple template,
HTML, welcome, that's the
title, and hello, $
curly brace, name,
closed curly brace.
Let's go back to our
HelloWorldFreemarkerStyle.
And I'm going to create a
template called Hello
Template, port the class, and
I get the template based on
its name, which is
just Hello.ftl.
And it's going to throw
an exception.
So I'm going to surround
this with a try catch.
I'll just make this catch
everything for now.
And I'm going to create a place
to put the output of the
template in a string writer.
And finally, I'm going to create
my map, which I'm going
to pass to FreeMarker as the set
of keys that I want to map
in my template.
So if you recall, we're looking
for a key of name.
So I'm going to add
that to Hello map.
And I'll add a name,
Hello Freemarker.
That's everything I need.
And now I just have to
process the template.
So I'm going to pass it the
map and the string writer.
Finally, I'm going to
print out the value
of the string writer.
And with luck, it should print
out Hello Freemarker.
Well, actually, it prints out
the whole web page, of course.
But inside, it says Hello
Freemarker, because it took
this map with a key of name
and a value of Freemarker,
processed the hello template,
and replaced the $name with
Freemarker and returned
the results.
And that's a basic introduction
to FreeMarker.
There's a lot more
with FreeMarker.
There's other directives and
ways to process the map, and
access it, and loop,
and so forth.
But this is enough
to get us going.