So in the last lesson, we talked
about fine-grained
control over writes.
Now I want to talk about
fine-grained
control over reads.
So by default, as you might
imagine, all reads are sent to
the primary.
So when you do a read from your
client application, the
query is sent to the primary and
the response comes back to
the primary.
And this is the default because
it makes applications
easy to reason about.
Let's imagine that I'm reading
from a secondary and my
queries are going here
and here while my
writes are going here.
What's possible is that you
could do an insert into the
primary and then do a query
from either of the
secondaries.
And because of replication lag
from the primary to the
secondary you may not
read your own write.
So you do the insert and then
you do a query, expecting to
have the query result include
the document you just inserted
and it's not there.
So that's why primary reads are
preferred because it makes
your applications easier
to reason about.
However there are situations
where reading from
secondaries is OK.
Sometimes your application can
tolerate a situation where
you're not necessarily reading
your own writes.
For example, you might have one
application doing inserts
and a totally different
application doing queries, in
which case they're not
coordinated anyway and having
a little replication
lag is OK.
We call this eventual
consistency, though, because
it breaks the strong consistency
guarantees of
reading your own writes
from the primary.
It's eventually consistent
because the inserts are
eventually guaranteed to make
it to the secondaries, but
since it's done with a
background replication thread
you don't know at what point the
replication will actually
complete and the writes will be
visible on the secondaries.
But if you know what you're
doing you can control where
your reads go to besides
the primary.
We call this read preference.
I'll just say read
pref for short.
And there's several different
read preferences.
So the default as primary,
which sends all
queries to the primary.
And that includes counts and
other query-like things.
There is secondary, which will
send all reads to randomly
selected secondary.
So either this or this.
There's secondary preferred.
What that does it will send
right to secondaries if there
is a secondary.
But if possible--
if both the secondaries
are down for example--
it will send the writes
to the primary.
On the other hand there's
primary preferred, which will
send all writes to the primary,
unless there's no
primary like during a failover,
in which case it
will send writes to
the secondary.
And finally there's nearest.
Nearest will send writes to
secondary or primary, it won't
distinguish between them.
For all of these read
preferences, except for
primary, the client
application--
the driver I should say--
will look at the ping times
between the client application
and each of the members of the
replica set, and will only
send reads to members of the
replica set that are within a
certain latency window
of the fastest.
So let's say, for example, the
ping time to this secondary is
five milliseconds.
The primary is eight
milliseconds.
But this secondary, say it's in
a different data center, is
50 milliseconds.
So if you use the read
preference of nearest, the
driver will see that this
secondary has the fastest ping
time of 5 milliseconds.
It'll scatter the reads to all
servers that are within 15
milliseconds of the fastest.
So it will distribute them
between the primary and the
secondary because 8 is 3
milliseconds lower than 5.
But it won't send any to this
secondary because there's 45
milliseconds between 50 and 5.
And this is dynamically
calculated by the driver.
It keeps sending pings every
once in while to each of the
members of the replica
set determining what
the ping times are.
OK, so that's the basics
of read preference.
Let's look at what it looks like
in a Java application.
So here is again our simple
application with MongoClient
DB and DB Collection.
In this case I have a query,
I do a Find, and I
print out the results.
If I want to change the read
preference I can do that by
setting it on the Find.
So I call Set Read Preference,
and let's say
we want to do nearest.
So it's Set Read Preference,
and there are a bunch of
static methods in the read
preference class for each of
the different kinds of
read preferences.
So readpreference.nearest is
what we're going to use here.
As with write concern, we can
set the read preference at
multiple levels.
So here, I'm setting it on the
cursor, but I can set a
default read preference
for my collection.
So I can make this primary
preferred.
I can set a read preference on
my DB primary, and I can also
set a default on the
client itself.
So it's very easy to use read
preferences in the Java driver.
As I said, there's these static
methods in the read
preference class returning the
various different kinds of
read preferences.
So primary, primary preferred,
nearest,
secondary, secondary preferred.
And you can set read preference
at any level from
MongoClient client to the DB, to
the DB Collection, all the
way to the individual query
on the DB cursor.
OK, no quiz for this one.