Sharding and replication are
almost always done together.
So whenever you've got a
sharded environment--
here I'm showing three shards,
s0, s1, and s2, and then a
mongos routing them.
The shards themselves
are replica sets.
And they're replica sets,
because otherwise, they
wouldn't be reliable.
You just have to expect that
when you're dealing with a
sharded environment.
And best practices dictate
that that's the way you
would set it up.
Next thing I wanted to point
out is that the mongos is
doing with the driver was doing
before in the sense that
the mongos is reconnecting to
members of the replica set,
because the mongos probably has
a connection all the way
through to the primary node of
the replica set in each of
these shards, and possibly
connections to the secondaries
if it's allowing secondary
reads.
So when there's failover within
a shard, it's the
mongos that's going
to reconnect.
And so the mongos has some
concept now of the seed list
and knows which of these
nodes are part of it.
The next thing that you should
realize is that there's still
this concept of write concern.
And there's still the j value
and w value and w timeout.
And those are going to be
passed right through.
So if your application specifies
that it requires
journaling to be true, let's
say, or w majority, a majority
of nodes need to see the write
before it's completed, then
your application is going
to specify that.
And the drivers are inside your
application or next to
your application drivers.
And that's going to
go to the mongos.
The mongos is going to route the
query to the appropriate
shard, the replica set.
And then that j and that write
concern are going to get
reflected in that final write.
So you should continue to think
about having to specify
those in the sense there's a
replicated environment here
and that those are
still meaningful.
And they're going to apply
to each of the nodes.
So if hit a multi-update, it'll
hit multiple nodes, then
in each node, if you said I
wanted the w value to be,
let's say two, and j to one,
then this mongos wouldn't get
an acknowledgement
for that write.
It wouldn't complete it until
all the different nodes
completed the write to
a majority of them.
And then it was committed to the
journal on the primary of
each of these replica sets.
Those are some things to keep
in mind as you're working in
this environment.
And the final point I'll make
is that usually mongos is
replicated itself.
There's probably a few these
hanging out here.
Typically, you run them on the
same box as the application
server itself, because they're
pretty lightweight.
And the driver is just the way
they can take multiple names
of hosts for replica set, they
could take multiple mongoses.
And it can't, for some reason,
attach to a mongos or connect
to a mongos, then it will
connect to another mongos.
So that's what I want to point
out to you about sharding plus
replication together,
that you've got
these replica set here.
And you have these mongoses
in front.
And everything you've learned
before about availability and
replication still applies.
It's just that it's passed
through to the various shards.
Let's do a quiz.
So suppose you want to run
multiple mongos routers for
redundancy.
What level of the stack will
assure that you can failover
to a different mongos from
within your application.
Is it the mongod, mongos, the
drivers, or the sharding
config servers?