Hi, this is Jeff again.
And this is a bit of a sidebar
about schema design to show
you how the flexible schema
capabilities of MongoDB make
it easy to import feeds
from around the web.
So the example I'll
use is Twitter.
Here I have the MongoDB
homepage for Twitter.
You can see the list
of tweets, the last
20 tweets or so.
And it turns out the
same information is
available in a feed.
So if I go to api.twitter.com,
and so forth, and then to
screen name, MongoDB,
I get a JSON feed
of the last 20 tweets.
And the structure is fairly
straightforward.
It has a created a date and ID,
the text of the tweets, a
nested user document that has
information about the user who
did the tweet.
And then, at the bottom, there's
some other things
about whether it was retweeted
and so forth, retweet count.
And there's 20 of them
in an array.
So I'm going to write a simple
Java program to take this data
from the Twitter feed and
throw it into a Mongo
collection.
So let's go over the program.
So I get the screen name.
I just default to MongoDB
for the screen name.
You can also get it from the
command line if you want,
through the first argument.
Then I call a method called get
the latest tweets, which
returns a list of DB objects
for the tweets.
And I'll show you that
method in a bit.
Then I'll create a Mongo client,
a DB collection for my
tweets collection, at
course.twitter.
Finally, I'll go through my
tweets and insert them all
into the database.
So let's first look at how we
got the tweet feed as a list
of DB objects.
So it's fairly straightforward.
I have a method called
getLatestTweets that takes the
screen name.
I construct a URL, including the
screen name, that's passed
in as a parameter.
I open the stream, and then I
just type the input stream
into a byte array
output stream.
It's not the most efficient
way of doing it, but it's
fairly straightforward.
I'm not worrying about
performance right now.
And then I take the
output stream and
turn it into a string.
And then the last step is
where the magic happens.
I take that string and call a
method called json.parse.
And this is part of
the Java driver.
And it basically will take a
JSON string, which can either
be a single document or a list,
and return the parsed
results as either a DB object
or a list of DB objects.
In this case, since it's
an array, it will
return it as a list.
So I return that list.
Then I iterate through
them one at a time
and insert each one.
So let's go to the shell, look
at our document, look at a
sample document.
Let's find one.
And all my data is here, which
is great, just like in the
feed that we saw
in the browser.
But I notice something I don't
like, which is that the ID
from the Twitter feed is
in here as a number.
But since it's not called
underscore, it could be the
driver created a _id for
me with an object ID.
I don't want that though because
what if I want to run
this twice, and not get
any duplicates?
Since a new object id will be
created each time, I can get
duplicate ids in
my collection.
So a simple thing to do is just
use this id as the _id.
So I wrote a method that
will do that already.
And it's called massageTweetId.
And it's very simple.
It just gets the ID, with no
underscore, removes that ID,
and then puts the value
of the id as _id.
And one other thing I noticed
is that the feed does not
contain the screen name
for each tweet.
And since I want to build a
store tweets from multiple
screen names in the same
collection, I want to add the
screen name here as well.
So let's do that up here too.
I'll say cur.put, screen name,
and get my screen name.
And now let's run this.
I'm going to drop my
collection first.
See what happens.
My tweet count is 20, and if I
look in the database, you'll
see that there's a
screen name here.
The screen name is MongoDB.
And my id is now the number
long that came
from the feed itself.
But let's see what happens
if I run this twice.
Not good-- exception.
I get a duplicate key exception
because I'm trying
to insert the same
document twice.
That's not what I want.
What I really want to do is, if
that tweet doesn't already
exist in the collection of
tweets, I want to insert it.
Otherwise, I want to,
essentially, ignore it.
Just leave it alone.
So we already learned
how to do this last
week, with an upsert.
So I'm going to change the
insert to an upsert using the
update method.
The criteria will just be the
id, which I could say just by
new basic DB object,
and cur.get, id.
And the document will
just be cur.
And then I want to say true to
make it an upsert, and then
false for multi.
And now, when I run this, I
get a tweet count of 20
because all those documents
were there already.
So let's just start again.
I'll drop everything.
Tweet count is zero now.
I'll run it once.
I get a tweet count of 20.
I run it again, get a
tweet count of 20.
That's because I'm
doing upserts.
The first time I ran it, sorted
of all the documents,
the next time, it didn't do
anything, essentially.
So let's go back once more.
And there's one other
thing I want to do.
I notice here that this user has
a lot of information here
that I don't really care.
And it's going to be duplicated
for every tweet.
So what I want to do is just
keep a little bit of data
about the user but throw
everything else away.
So I want to keep the id of the
user, the name, and the
screen name.
And one other thing I don't like
about this is the created
at field is a string
representing a date, as
opposed to a date, which will
make it harder to do data
arithmetic if I want
to ever to querying
on the created update.
So I'm going to massage the
document a little bit before I
put it in here.
And I already rewrote this
method, which I'll show you.
It's massageTweet.
Let's take a look.
I do two things.
I create a simple date format
that matches that pattern.
And then I get the created at
as a string and then pass it
to parse of simple date format,
and reput it back as
the value of created at.
So I'm taking the string value
created at and turning it into
a date, and reinserting it
back into the document.
And then for my user sub
documents, the way I get rid
of all the extra fields, I do a
cur.getUser, pass that to a
DB object, and then I iterate
over the key set, so all the
keys and user.
And if the key doesn't equal
ID, name, or screen name, I
remove it by calling
keyIterator.remove.
So let's run this again.
My tweet count is still 20.
But since I did upsert with
replace, the documents should
now look the way
I want them to.
So my created at field
is now an ISO date
instead of a string.
And my user document just has
these three fields, id, name,
and screen name.
And now I have my data, and
I can do searches on it.
So I can do, let's see.
Since I want to find all
documents where the retweet
count is greater than 5 and
count them, I can do that with
a simple query.
Let's say I want to find all
tweets where the text of the
document is the word China.
I can do that with a
regular expression.
MongoDB is coming to China.
And finally, the last thing I
wanted to show you is, I can
add tweets for a different
screen name.
So if I change this to 10gen,
instead of MongoDB, I'll get
the last 20 10gen
tweets as well.
So now my tweet count is 40.
And let's search for tweets
containing MongoDB.
And you can see them here.
Let's just look at screen
name instead.
And you can see, there's a lot
more tweets containing MongoDB
for the screen name MongoDB
than for 10gen.
OK, that's it.
And there's no quiz.