In this problem you're given a
collection of students and
you're being asked to remove the
lowest homework grade for
each student.
You can see that there's one
document per student--
right here we're looking at
Mariette Batdorf's document--
and that there's a scores
key with a array of
assessments within it.
And you'll need to iterate
through this list and then
find the lowest homework--
so in this case, the
homework for 7.6--
and you'll need to remove it.
And the way you'll do that is
by creating a new list and
then doing an update statement
to the collection, isolating
the record that you're looking
at, and updating the scores
collection with the new
list of assessments.
And then after you're done with
that, you're going to run
an aggregation command that we
give you to find the student
with the highest average
in the class.