OK.
Let's take you through the
solution to this problem.
Now again, we have to remove the
lowest homework score for
each student.
And that's going to be done by
finding each student and then
going through the list of the
assessments and finding the
lowest one.
It's a little bit tricky
compared to some of the other
code that we've written so
far for the homeworks.
So we start out by creating this
Remove Lowest function.
And you can see we're
connecting with the
MongoClient right here.
The MongoClient class to the
local MongoD server.
Getting database school.
And then we're getting the
collection, students.
Now we're going to do a Find
across the entire collection
so we hit every document.
And now we're going
to iterate through
each of these students.
Now, we're going to get a DB
Object out of this collection
if we iterate across it.
And then we're going to call Get
Scores on each one to get
the scores array.
And we're going to cast that to
a basic DB List, because we
know that it is a list.
And you can see here I've
created a variable of DB List.
We need a sentinel value.
We need to know when we've
found the lowest one.
So we set this variable,
minScoreObj, null, initially.
And we set the minScore
that we've seen to
the Max Double Value.
In this collection, there's no
value above 100, so you could
probably set it to something
lower than that.
But this will certainly work.
And then down here, you can see
what we're doing is we're
iterating across the
scores collection.
Now, this is an array list.
And so we can iterate
directly across it.
What we're going to get out of
it is just simple objects.
Now, we know that they're much
more than that, but we'll have
to cast it after we reiterate
through it.
So we're iterating through it
using this for each command.
And then the object that we get
when we cast it to Basic
DB Object and put it in here.
Then we get the score
and the type.
Now, we're only interested
in homeworks.
So if the type was homework
and the score is less than
minScore, then we remembered
the value, the score.
Put it in the score variable.
And remember the object.
We do this.
When we're done, we're going
to have minScore pointed to
the lowest score and minScoreObj
pointing to the
object corresponding to that.
And this object, of course, came
from this scores list.
So now we're going
to go down here.
We're going to remove the
minScoreObj from the scores
array list.
It's a standard Remove
command.
And after that, we're going to
call the Update command,
MongoDB Update command.
We're going to find the student
record that has an
underscore ID equal to the ID
that we're working with.
And we're going to create a Set
command setting the scores
value to the scores key to the
scores array that we've been
working with and manipulating.
So this will remove
the lowest score.
So let's go through there
and watch it work.
I guess I'll show you the
values do change.
Let me do that first.
So if you run the aggregation
that we gave you before you
removed the lowest score for
each student, you see that
Student 85 has the
lowest average.
Now let's run this.
I ran it.
Now I'm going to go through
and look again.
Run the aggregation
command again to
find the lowest average.
And we're going to learn
about aggregation
in a follow-on unit.
And you can see the highest
average in the class is now
this student with ID 37.
So that has changed because
of our removal of data.
And we can see that the
data is removed.
So let's do that.
So you can see that now each of
the students has only three
assessments.
All right.
And that's the solution
to this problem.