So this is Jeff Yemin again.
And I'll be talking to the next
few lectures about CRUD
using the Java driver.
So if you recall from Richard's
lectures about the
shell, our operations for CRUD
are called Insert, Find,
Update, and Remove.
Those are the operations in the
shell, and they have the
same names in the Java driver.
Before we get into those, we
need to talk for a little
while about how documents are
represented in the Java driver.
So one form of the
insert method
takes a single document.
So the question is, what is the
type of the parameter that
we passed insert.
So you might think at first
glance that we pass a map.
That would be a good guess.
And furthermore, we might think
that that is a map using
generics of string to object.
But there's a problem
with using map.
And the problem is that, since
these documents are used all
over the place, for all
the operations--
Insert, Find, Update,
and Remove--
in some cases, the order
of keys within the
map actually matter.
So since not all map
implementations guarantee the
ordering of keys, it's a little
dangerous if we use map
as the type of the documents.
So we don't do that.
The next thing you might
think is that we use an
implementation of map the
guarantees order, like Linked
HashMap, but that was felt to be
a little too constraining,
because there might be some
cases where you'd want to use
a different kind of map.
So we don't use that either.
What actually is used is an
interface called DBObject,
which is an interface defined
in the Java driver.
And DBObject is a
map-like thing.
It has a lot of the same methods
of map, but it's not
actually a map.
They could have actually
implemented map, but for
reasons that are lost
to history, it does
not implement map.
And at this point, it's not
possible to retrofit it
without breaking binary
compatibility.
But we do use DBObject,
which is an interface.
And there is a concrete class,
which also is provided by the
Java driver, which implements
DBObject.
And that class is called
Basic DBObject.
So DBObject is the type
of all the parameters
to all these methods.
It's used for representing
documents and also for
representing sort criteria that
we past-defined, field
selection for find, update
operations for update like
dollar set, and so forth.
So let's take a look at how
this looks in code.
Let's create a class called
Document Representation Test.
And we're not going to
actually do any CRUD
operations.
We're just going to show you
how to create documents.
Add a main method, and
create a variable
of type Basic DBObject.
You can see that ultimately
Basic
DBObject implements DBObject.
And I should say furthermore
that Basic DBObject ultimately
extends LinkedHashMap.
And LinkedHashMap, if you don't
know this class, is a
class that guarantees that the
order of the keys when you
iterate is the same as
the insertion order.
So I can do things like doc.put
and start adding
fields and their values.
I can use different
types, obviously.
So I can say doc.put birth date
equals new date, some
random date.
I can use Booleans.
And I can use numbers.
I'm eight years old.
That gives you a nice
flat document.
But if you remember from
Richard's lectures, documents
in Mongo can have nested
substructure, just like JSON.
So I can do things like add
a raise, like this.
Languages, all right.
And I can say Java, C++, and I
can also add subdocuments.
So a subdocument is just
represented as
another Basic DBObject.
Let me show you a few tricks
with subdocuments here.
I want to do this all as one
expression, so one thing I can
do to shorten this up is I'm
going to say there's an
address field, and it's
a subdocument.
And one of the things you can do
with Basic DBObject in the
constructor is [INAUDIBLE]
initial key-in value.
So I can say my street
is 20 Main Street.
And then I can call a method
called append on Basic
DBObject to append additional
values.
So let's say town, Westfield,
append, zip.
And the nice thing about append
is that it just returns
itself, which lets you chain
the append methods.
I can create a whole complicated
document here in a
single expression.
So that's basically, when
it comes to document
representation with the Java
driver, the CRUD methods that
you'll see.
In the upcoming lecture is Tic
DBObjects and the Fine Method
returns DBObject.
But when you actually want to
create new instances of
DBObject, you would typically
create instances of the class
Basic DBObject, which is a
LinkedHashMap that guarantees
the ordering of the keys.
I think it's time
for a quiz now.
How would you create a document
using the Java driver
with this JSON structure?
An _id field with the value
user1, and an interests field
with a value that's an array
with two values--
basketball and drumming.