So now it's time to insert
our first document into--
I'm going to be using
the Java driver.
So if you recall from Document
Representation Test, we saw
how to create a document
using BasicDBObject.
So we'll be doing the same for
Insert, but I'll start a new
class for this.
Call it Insert Tests.
And we'll create our name.
You might recall from last week
how we bootstrapped our
self for the Java driver, but
I'll review it again, since
it's been a little while.
We start with a MungoClient
And it throws in a host
exception, so I'll add that
to the method signature.
Then I need to choose
a database.
Call it Course DB, and I
can get that from the
client using getDB.
And then I need a collection
which is a type DB collection.
I'll just call this
collection.
And I get the collection from
the course database.
I'll call the collection
InsertTest.
And next I need an
object to insert.
So I'll create a document.
I'll create a very
simple document.
X with value one.
And notice I'm storing it into
a DB object, even though it's
a basic DB object.
That's just to prove that
the insert method
can accept a DB object.
And finally I insert it
with insert method.
I write the doc, and that's
all there is to it.
But first, actually, let
me print it out.
I'm going to print it out before
I did the insert and
again after.
So let's run it.
And you can see when I printed
it out before, it just has x
of one, which we'd expect.
But when I printed it out after
the insert, you can see
that it has another
field called _id.
You probably remember this
from earlier in the week.
Just like the shell, if you
didn't already have an _id
field in the document you
insert, the Java driver will
create _id field for you, and
give it a new object ID.
And this just syntactic sugar.
It's essentially shorthand
for this--
putting an ID in here
explicitly and
saying New Object ID.
Object ID is of type
org.bison.types.objectid,
which it imported
automatically.
If we do, this you'll see the
same thing, except in this
case, since I put the _id
in the basic DB object
explicitly, you can see that
it's the same in both cases--
the same value of
the object ID.
So I can show you what it
looks like in the shell.
Let me put a drop-in
here, just so the
collection's empty.
Now let's look at the shell.
And insert test, so I can
say db.inserttest.
Db.InsertTest.find, and you can
see there's my documents
that I inserted.
I'm going to do a couple
of other things.
First, what I want to do is
show you that you can also
insert a list of documents using
a single insert method
call, instead of just one.
So let's create doc2 and give it
x2 as a field in its value.
And instead of inserting a
single doc, I'll say I'll
insert both of them together,
using the
arrays.aslist method.
And let's run that.
And if you look in the database,
you'll now see that
there's two documents, each with
a distinct object ID and
a distinct value for x.
So the last thing I want to show
you is the behavior of
insert when you insert
a duplicate document.
So let's get rid of
Document Two.
We'll do our insert like
we did before.
But I'm going to do it twice--
I'll insert the same
document twice.
If we run that, we should expect
to see an exception the
second time.
And we do.
And it's a section of type
duplicate key, or
MungoException duplicate key,
and it says that there's a
duplicate key error with
this object ID,
which is as we'd expect.
So the first insert succeeded
and the second one failed.
Whether I add the ID explicitly
doesn't really
matter, so if I take that out
and run it again, we get the
same error.
And that's pretty much
it for inserts.
So we saw that we can insert
into a collection either using
the single document insert form
or a list of documents,
and that if we try to insert a
document with the same _id as
an already-existing document in
the collection, we'll get a
duplicate key exception.
Let's do a quiz.
The question is, do you
expect the second
insert below to succeed?
So I create a basic db
object here, with no
explicit _id field.
We insert it, then call
removefield that will remove
the _id field from this
document, and
then I insert again.
So the first option is no,
because the _id will be a
duplicate in the collection.
Second is no, because the
removefield call will remove
the entire document.
Third is yes, because the
removefield call will remove
the _ID key added by the driver
in the first insert.
And finally yes, because the
driver always adds a unique
_id field on insert.