So in the last lecture, we
talked about how to insert
data into Mongo DB using
the Java driver.
And now we're going to talk
about how to do simple
queries, including review of
Find one, how to find all the
documents in a collection, and
how to count the documents in
a collection.
So as not to waste time, I
already wrote the boilerplate
code, same as last time,
creating a client database and
a collection, then dropping
the collection.
And since we're querying, I also
wrote a little code to
insert some documents
into the collection.
So I'm inserting 10 documents,
each with an object ID for the
_id, and a field x with a random
integer between 0 and
99 as a value.
And now let's go
to the queries.
So let's look at a
simple Find one.
Again, this is review
from last week.
So we can say DBObject.doc,
or one=collection.findone.
And we can print it out.
Let's see what that does.
Here's the printout.
Remember that the _id
will be created
automatically by the driver.
And here's the random
x value of 86.
OK, so that's Find one--
pretty simple.
Now let's look at Find, which is
a little bit more verbose,
and I'll explain why
in a moment.
For Find, we actually have
to create a cursor.
So we call collection.find,
which returns a cursor.
And as you learn from Richard
earlier, there's actually a
cursor on the server.
The reason we have to save it
like this is because we're
going to need to close
it in a while.
So I'm going to put this inside
a finally block--
try finally, rather--
and say cursor.close here, to
make sure the cursor gets
closed even if I exit up
normally from the try.
And inside the cursor, I'll say
while (cursor.hasNext),
and then DBObject
cur=cursor.next.
And then I'll print it out.
Let's see what this does first,
and then we'll talk a
little bit more about it.
So it prints out all
the documents--
all 10 documents-- in
the collection.
The cursor is an iterator.
So if you look at DBCursor you
can see that it's an iterator
of DBObject.
So that's where that hasNext and
the Next method come from.
And they have the semantics
of Java iterators.
So the hasNext method will
return true if calling x will
actual return a document.
Otherwise it will
return false.
And next will return
a document.
And if you call next when
hasNext returned false, it's
going to throw an exception.
And one important thing to
remember is that you need to
call close.
With 10 documents, it doesn't
matter, because there won't be
a cursor on the server.
But if you are iterating through
hundreds of documents
or thousands, you have to
remember to close the cursor,
especially if your loop
terminates abnormally--
like if you throw an exception
within this wild loop, you
want to make sure that cursor is
closed, even if you didn't
exhaust it on the server.
Finally, let's talk
about count.
Count's very simple, also.
You can just say
collection.count, we
can print it out.
Let's see what that does.
Should print out 10.
And it does.
And that's it.
That's the basics of Findone,
Find, and Count.
In the next lesson, we'll talk
about how to limit the results
based on a query.
OK, let's look at a quiz.
In the following code snippet,
please enter the simplest one
line of Java code that would be
needed in place the XXXX to
make it print one document from
the people collection
created here, assuming there
is a document there.
Don't worry about white space.
I believe it will be script, but
don't put any extra things
in there, like comments
or anything like that.
And notice also that the print
line is already in the bottom,
so you don't have to actually
print it yourself.