Hi again.
So in the last segment, we
learned how to do find one
find and count, but we didn't
look at how to limit the
results based on any sort
of query criteria.
So that's what we're going
to do in this segment.
So just to start things off, I
wrote a little program, which
we're going to modify.
We create a Mongo client, a
DB and a DB collection.
Drop the collection, just
like we've been doing.
And I changed the insert
a little bit.
I'm still inserting 10
documents, but I'm inserting
documents with two fields now,
just so we can construct some
more interesting queries.
There's a field x, and its
value is a random integer
between 0 and 1.
And a second field y, which
is a random integer
between 0 and 99.
And towards the bottom of the
program, I'm counting the
number of documents
in the collection.
And I'm finding them all and
proofing out each one by
creating a cursor and calling
has next and while loop, and
calling next for each
document, and
then closing the cursor.
So let's run this, and we should
expect a count of 10,
and 10 documents.
So let's see what
it looks like.
And we do have a count of 10,
and 10 documents you can see x
is either 0 or 1, and y falls
between 0 and 99.
So now let's limit
the results.
And we're going to do that
with a criteria, which is
represented as a document.
And we know that in Java, when
we want to create a document
we use basic DB object.
So I can say DB object,
call it query equals
new, basic DB object.
And let's query for documents
where the value of x is 0.
So I've created a simple,
basic DB object.
Basically a query by example,
where there's a field x with a
value of 0.
And now I'm going to take that
query and plug it into my
method calls.
So I'm just going to put count
of query and find query.
And on average, since we're
using a random number
generator, we should expect to
see around five documents.
But it will vary based on the
random number generator.
So in this case we found four
matching documents, all of
them have 0 for x, and
presumably all the other
documents have got a
value of 1 for x.
So a simple query which limited
the results, both for
count and for find.
We can also create
a compound query.
And similar to the shell, we're
going to do that just by
appending to this document,
representing our criteria.
So let's say I want to select,
I want to query for all
documents where x is 0 and
y is greater than 10
and less than 90.
So I can do that by appending a
query criteria for y, where
the value of the criteria is
another basic DB object where
y is greater than 10
and less than 90.
So let's run this again, and we
should expect to see only
documents where x is 0 and
y is between 10 and 90.
And that is the case.
We run it, we can run it several
times so we can see
that y is always falling
between that range.
The number of documents returned
varies based on the
random number generator, but it
always matches the criteria.
Now, there's one other way
that the driver offers to
query, because you can see here
that we're using these
strings, greater than, dollar
GT and dollar LT.
And in some cases it would be
nicer to use a class that gave
you some more helper
methods for
commonly used query operators.
And the Java driver does have
such a class, and it's called
Query Builder.
And I'll show you how to use
this by creating a query using
Query Builder that is equivalent
to the query we
just created with
basic DB object.
So we do it like this.
Say Query Builder dot start,
and we'll say x.
And if we want to just do an
equality match, we use is.
And we could say 0, so we're
saying x is 0, and because
query criteria are implicitly
entered together, but here we
have an explicit method
and, and we'll say y
greater than 10.
Less than, we'll change
it to 70 this time.
And if we go down here, we
can change our method
calls to say builder.
But we can't pass a builder to
count because it's expecting a
DB object for the criteria.
But the builder can create a DB
object using the get method
of the builder.
So we change that to builder dot
get, builder dot get here,
and we're no longer using query,
but I'll just leave
that in, and we'll rerun it.
In this case, we only
have one match.
We can run it a few
more times.
This time we have four, but
essentially the same results
using Query Builder
as for DB object.
So it really depends
on what you like.
Some people like to just use
basic DB object, and some
people like to use Query
Builder, but it's really your
choice which one you
want to use.
All right, let's
go to the quiz.
So the quiz is given a
collection of documents with
two fields named Type and Score,
what is the correct
line of code to find all
documents where type is equal
to Quiz and score is greater
than 20 and less than 90?
And this is multiple choice, but
you can select more than
one answer.