OK, so in this lecture, we're
going to talk about selecting
the fields from documents
in your queries.
So the code that I have here is
similar to what we saw in
the last lecture.
Just to make the code shorter,
I broke out the random number
to the top.
And I've added a third the
field to the document, z,
which is a number between
zero and 999.
I'm using the same queries using
query builder, querying
for documents where x is 0, and
y is greater than 10, and
less than 70.
Let's just run it to
make sure it works.
It only matched one document.
Let's run it once more.
Still one and zero.
All right, that's better.
So this matched three
documents.
And you see we have the ID
fields and x, y, and z.
But it's kind of silly to get
the x field because we're
querying for x is zero, so why
bother selecting x, since we
know it's going to be zero?
So can we get rid of x from
our query results?
The answer is yes.
We do that using the second
parameter to the find method
to select the fields that we
want to have returned.
So there's a few ways
to do this.
But since what we're trying to
do here is get everything but
x, we can do it by saying
x is false.
So we create a document where
x is false, and that just
means return everything but
x, and let's run it again.
And now we have the ID,
and we have y, and we
have z, but no x.
Now let's say that what we
actually want is only y.
We don't want z or x.
So rather than saying x false,
y false, we can just change
this to y and true
to get only y.
And x and z are gone.
And we have y.
But we also have this ID.
And usually, we're going
to want the ID.
But in the cases where we don't,
we can exclude it by
appending _id, false, saying we
do not want the id field.
And if we run that again,
we only get y,
which is what we wanted.
OK, now let's do a quiz.
So given a variable, name
students, of type
DBCollection, so we have a
DBCollection of student
documents, which of the
following lines of code can be
used to find all documents in
the collection, retrieving
only the phone number field.
So we have student.find,
a new basic DBObject.
Phone number 1, a pen
idea of zero.
Students.find new basic DBObject
phone number one,
students.find new basic
DBObject, new basic DBObject
phone number 1, append id 0,
and students.find new basic
DBObject, phone number
1, append ID of
0, new basic DBObject.