This lecture will round out our
discussion of querying use
in the Java driver.
We'll discuss sort,
skip and limit.
So it's pretty straightforward.
For the coding, I'm going
to use the same document
structures we did with
dot notation.
I have lines basically with an
"_id," "start," with x and y,
and "end" with x and y.
And just to review, it looks
like-- let me do a find to
show you what it produces
without any criteria.
And you can see, each document
has a "start" field and an
"end" field.
And "start" and "end" each have
x- and y-coordinates.
And there's an "_id" as well.
So let's look at
sorting first.
So to sort we achieve a method
call off of find.
So find returns a cursor.
So when we do sort, we're just
modifying the cursor before
the query's actually sent
to the database.
So we do it by calling sort.
And we pass it--
as you might have guessed--
a DBObject, in this case a
BasicDBObject, which will
represent our sort criteria.
So let's for starters sort
"_id", but descending instead
of ascending.
So we'll say "_id", -1.
And when we run it, we should
see that the "_id"s are now
sorted from the highest value
to the lowest, from 9 to 0.
So that's pretty
straightforward.
Now, skip and limit
are just as easy.
We just keep chaining method
calls onto the cursors.
So let's we want to skip the
first two documents in the
sort order.
So if we do that,
we should expect
that 9 and 8 are skipped.
And that's indeed the case.
So we have 7, 6, 5 4, 3 2, 1.
And finally limit.
Let's say we want to only get
back the first three after
skipping two.
We can do that with limit(3).
We run it again, and we
should see 7, 6 and 5.
And indeed we do.
So we can also use dot notation
and sort just like we
did with field selection
and with querying.
So let's say we want to sort
"start.y" descending.
We can do that just by
saying "start.y".
And we see that now
it's sorted by
"start.y" 87, 78, 77.
And finally, we can also have
multiple sort criteria.
So if we want to sort on
"start.x" followed by
"start.y" we can do that just by
chaining those criteria in
the DBObject.
So let's "start.x", 1 and
we append "start.y", -1.
So it should sort of all the
x's first and then when the
x's are equal, it
will sort by y.
Let's have a little
higher limit.
Just to show it.
So you can see that the start.x
0s come first and then
within that, we're sorting by
y, and then all the 1s, and
sorting descending by y.
OK, time for a quiz.
So the quiz is, suppose you had
the following documents in
a collection named things.
"_id"s are from 0 through
3 and then value
10, 5, 7, and 20.
If you perform the following
query in the Java driver,
find, sort on value, descending,
skip 2, limit 1,
which document would
be returned?
Would it be document with
_id=0 1, 2, or 3?