This is our last lecture on CRUD
using the JAVA driver,
and I'm going to introduce you
to one more technique that you
can use with MongoDB, which we
actually haven't seen yet when
we've been in the shell, and
it's called find and modify.
Find and modify provides an
interesting capability which
allows you to, in one atomic
operation, find a document,
modify it, and return it.
Again, all atomically.
So, to motivate the discussion
around find and modify, I'll
give you an example of a service
that you could develop
easily with find and modify.
So it's a service that provides
unique ranges of
numbers for a given ID.
So it allows you to specify
an ID for a counter.
I chose ABC to use here.
And the function basically takes
a counter ID, the number
of numbers needed, so the size
of the range, and then the
collection to store
the counters in.
The method returns the first
number in the range, and it's
guaranteeing that the caller
of this method has unique
access, essentially, or it will
be the only one given the
numbers from first up to
num needed minus 1.
And I do this three times with
the same counter ID, ABC.
I ask for two numbers, then
three and 10, and I print out
the range for each one.
So the first time, it should
print out range one to two,
and then three to five,
and then six to 15.
I haven't actually written the
function yet, so I'm going to
do that now.
So let's see how we
can write getRange
using find and modify.
So, find and modify returns a
document, I'll call it doc.
And I'll say
collection.findAndModify, and
there's a lot of arguments to
find and modify for this
particular use case,
but the first
argument is always a query.
And I'm querying for a
document with the ID
that's passed in.
The second argument is the
fields I want back.
I'm just going to pass in null
for fields, because I don't
care about getting all the
fields back in this case.
The third argument is sort
criteria, which we're not
going to use here, so
just going to say
null for sort as well.
The fourth argument is whether
the document should be removed
after it's modified.
So I'm going to say false,
because I need to maintain the
value of my counter.
But there are use cases were
remove is important,
but not this one.
The next argument is the actual
update that I want to
do, the modification I want
to make to this document.
So what do I actually
want to do here?
Every document needs to maintain
the current value of
the counter.
So what I'm going to say here
is I want to increment the
value of the counter
field by what?
I want to increment
it by range.
So, based on how large a range
the user's requested.
And the last two parameters
are return new and upsert.
Find and modify lets you decide
whether you want to get
the contents of the document
either before or after the
modification that you perform
through find and modify.
In this case, I want the value
after, because I'm also going
to say true for upsert because
if the counter doesn't already
exist, I want to create it.
So if I said false for return
new, the first time I called
this method of a particular
ID, I'd get back null.
I don't deal with null, so I'm
just going to say true here.
Close that already.
And then I need to return the
value of the counter.
So I'm going to return
doc.get counter to
cast that to an integer.
But if I do that, then I'm going
to get the value of the
counter after the range,
and I want the
value before the range.
So I'm going to return counter
minus range plus 1, just to
account for the off by one error
for the subtraction.
So if I run this, I get
back what I'd expect.
First time I call the method,
again, with counter ID of ABC,
I need two, so my range
is from one two.
The second time, I call
it from three,
so I get three back.
So it's three to five.
And the third time, I want
10 numbers back, so
I get six to 15.
And at the end, I print out the
value of the collection.
You can see that there's a
single document in the
collection whose ID is
ABC, as we'd expect.
The counter now is 15.
And that's it with find
and modified.
As you can see from the number
of parameters, there's a lot
of permutations of those
parameters that'll let you
achieve different effects.
But this is just to give you a
flavor of the kind of things
you can achieve with
find and modify.