Hi, this is Andrew again.
In this class, we're going to
use a blog as a project that
we're going to use throughout
the course.
And you're going to build
different parts of it.
This week we're going to work on
three different parts-- the
author sign up, the author log
in, and the author log out.
The authors are the only ones
who need to sign in and sign
out of our blog.
And the idea is that viewers
can use it anonymously.
So let's go through what
the user interface
looks like for this.
Here I have our web browser.
And we're going to be
running the blog.
So here I'm going to first
show you how to
get the blog started.
So when you download the code
for this week's homework
assignment, homework problem
three, you'll see a couple
different things, including
a validation script
and a small run file.
In the run file, you'll see
there's this mvn command that
will run it.
You can import the
pom into an IDE.
So you don't necessarily need
to run it using mvn.
But it should work if you
run it using mvn.
So I'm going to do that.
So you can see here it started,
and it started on
port 80/82.
So if we go to port 80/82 and we
hit return, we can see that
we have a placeholder
for our blog.
Now, we only have three
URL routes that are
currently set up.
One of them is to sign up for
the blog, and another one is
to log in, another one
is to log out.
So I'm going to sign up for
the blog right here.
And I'm going to type
my user name--
erlichson.
And I'm going to give
myself a password--
fubar.
And then I'm going
to hit Submit.
And when I do that, you can see
that I'm redirected to the
welcome page, which welcomes
me by name.
And let's go to my home
or to my log out page.
So if we just log out of the
blog, then I can log
back into the blog.
If I type the wrong password in,
it'll say invalid login.
And if I type the right password
in, I go back here.
So there were three different
URLs that
we implemented there--
log in, log out, and
the sign up URL.
Now, I'm showing you a completed
version of the
homework assignment where the
code has been inserted by me
so that the whole thing actually
works properly.
But you'll have to do that part
yourself in the actual
assignment.
And then if you look here and
see what happened internally--
I'm going to quit out of here.
I run Mongo.
I'm going to use blog.
And I'm going to look at
the user's collection.
And you can see right here
there's an entry in the users
collection--
id erlichson, a hash version
of my password along with
[? assault ?]
in this users table.
And there's also something
in the sessions table.
And the sessions code we're
going to leave in for you.
But the sessions code,
there's a long,
random, and my username.
So that's how the user interface
works and what you
should see in database.
And so now I'm going to go over
the overall structure of
this project to show you what it
looks like so you know how
to work on it.