OK, let's go over the
blog internals now.
Now there's two different
parts of this project
for the most part.
There's the view, made up of
these as FTL templates that
are processed by FreeMarker.
And then there's the controller
and the model,
which is in Java code and uses a
Spark framework for handling
of the routes, in the sense that
Spark framework is really
part of the view as well.
And so I'm going to show you
those two different parts.
This is the IntelliJ IDE.
You are welcome to use
whatever IDE you
want or none at all.
I started by importing the
palm file to get in here.
The main class is this
BlogController file.
And this BlogController
instantiates the other
objects, the session data access
object and the user
data access object that handle
the session management and the
user data management.
We can see right here at the
top, we connect to MongoDB.
We actually called a
new BlogController.
And then in there, we
connect to MongoDB.
Here's the BlogController
right here.
And you can see it calls
mongoClient and gets
DB("blog").
It creates the two other data
access objects, the user and
session data access objects.
Also sets our port
up to be 80, 82.
Now if we look at any given
route, we can see here--
this is the initialized
route command.
You can see that we're--
let's say if you're looking
at the sign-up route, this
handles the post to sign up, but
is also a GET request to
sign up, which is in some ways
easier to understand.
It creates a new FreeMarker
based route, tells it that it
handles the path "signup",
and it presents on this
"signup.ftl." template.
And for that one, it just puts a
bunch of starting values for
the form elements.
Now over here, we've got these
templates, down here.
Let's look at one of these
templates, for instance, the
welcome template.
The welcome template.
It welcomes you by name and has
a few other links in it.
This is a FreeMarker
convention.
So we have in the middle of an
HTML page, $, then this curly
brace, and then this literal
username, which is used to
look up a value.
So it looks it up in a hash,
the hash that was set up
before the template
was invoked.
If we look here in
BlogController, you can see
here we're presenting the
welcome template, this is
actually a GET request.
You can see that it gets the
cookie out of the request, and
then it looks up in the
sessions, using a session data
access object to find
the full username.
If it can't find it, it just
says, I'm sorry, you don't
seem to be logged in.
But if it does find it, then
it creates a new HashMap,
which it puts in this
variable route.
Then it puts a key
value pair in.
The key is "username", and the
value is the actual username.
And then it calls
template.process passing that
HashMap, which the FreeMarker
process uses to fill it in
when it combines the data with
the template itself.
So for this week you're going to
be filling stuff in in the
user data access object that's
going to read things out of
the user collection and write
things in the user collection.
And I'm not going to show you
that class because it has the
code that you'll
need to write.
So I want to keep that
hidden right now.
If you look here in the blog
itself, you can see it's just
this placeholder thing that you
saw when you went to the
blog, which is, this is my
placeholder for the blog.
And in the subsequent weeks,
we're going to fill this in
with more templates that we're
going to give you, an
additional class here, so that
you can access the posts and
you'll be writing the code to
do the MongoDB part of that.
All right.
So that's how the internals
of this blog system work.