Let's go over the answer
to this problem.
All the code you needed to add,
you can put in the user
DAO object, the data
access object.
There were two places
you needed to work.
The first one was in this
addUser function.
And you would need to create a
Basic DB Object then add the
key value pairs for
the username,
underscore id username.
And the password, which is
going to be the hashed
password that comes
out of this make
password hash function.
Now, if the email is present,
and then you also add it to
the document.
So it depends on whether or not
the person gave an email
when they signed up.
Then you insert it right here.
And normally it will insert
without a problem.
But if the user name has been
used before, then you'll get a
Duplicate Key error which you
handle by returning false from
this function.
Now, to check when they log in,
you have to add code to
validateLogin.
And in that case, you simply
find one creating a new Basic
BD Object with the key id
set to the username.
So that's the way you'd
find the right
document for the user.
And then, you check right here
to see if it's null.
And if it's null, then
you return null.
And that's it.
So we gave you a lot of this
code, and that's all you
needed to do to make the blog
work for sign up and sign out.