Now we've learned about replica
sets, let's look now
at how we connect to a replica
set using the Java driver.
So first, I just wrote a simple
application which
creates a MongoClient client
connected to local host 27017,
creates a collection
replica.test in the course
database, and then just inserts
a bunch of documents,
one after the other, and sleeps
for a half a second
between each.
And if we run this, it
just looks like this.
And if you look in the shell,
we see those documents.
And that's fine.
But the way I've configured this
instance, it's actually
part of a replica set.
And we can see that by
running rs.status.
You can see that 27017 is the
primary and 27018 is the
secondary, and there's a couple
more secondaries on
019, 020, and then
arbiter on 021.
So what happens if I step
down the primary?
So I say rs.stepDown.
And now, if you look at the
replica [? set ?] status,
there's an election going on.
There's no primary yet.
And now 270120 has been
made the primary.
So let's run this
program again.
And let's see what happens.
Well, it fails, because
it's saying it's not
talking to the master.
And that's because I'm connected
directly to local
host 27017, and that's no
longer the primary.
And you can only write
to the primary.
So I can fix this by changing
it to 27020.
And that works, but that's
rather annoying.
Because you don't want to have
to change your client
application every time
that there's a
failover of your primary.
So how do we address this?
Well, it's actually
very simple.
Instead of providing MongoClient
with a single
server address, as
we did here, we
provided it with a seedlist.
The way I could do a seedlist
is to pass it a
list of server addresses.
So instead of just passing
270120, I'm going to pass
several more from the
same replica set.
So I'll pass it 017,
018, and 019.
And let's see what
happens now.
So the primary--
I stepped down, but the way
I have my replica set
configured, 27017 has a higher
priority, which you can see
with rs.comf.
It's a priority five,
so it keeps
reelecting itself primary.
So 27017 is the primary.
If I run this, even if
I don't list 27017--
so let's change this to 27021.
So notice, the primary is not
in this list anymore.
If I run this, it
works just fine.
And the reason is because the
MongoClient instance will use
the seedlist to discover all the
members of the replica set
and figure out which one's the
primary and which are the
secondaries.
And based on that, it will
send the inserts to the
correct member of the replica
set, which in
this case, is 27017.
Doing that again, and
it works fine.
And if I stepDown
27017 again--
let's wait for a primary
to be elected.
Now 27019 is the primary,
which is in my seedlist.
And I run it, and
it works fine.
Let's do a quiz.
If you leave a replica set
node out of the seedlist
within the driver,
what will happen?
The missing node will not be
used by the application.
The missing node will be
discovered as long as you list
at least one valid node.
The missing node will be used
for reads but not for writes.
Or the missing node
will be used for
writes, but not for reads.