In the last lesson, we saw how
to connect to a replica set
using the Java driver,
using a seed list.
And we'll continue with the same
example in this lesson.
But here, what I want to show
you is what could happen when
a node in your replica set that
you're connected to goes
down, or if there's a failover
and the primary
as long as the primary.
We saw that a little bit
in the last lesson.
But let's just review here.
So I have the same program.
I have my seed list,
and I'll run it.
And we'll see that we're
inserting documents.
And if we go and step down the
primary, the shell, you see
that the application through
an exception--
a MongoException--
saying no replica set members
available in the seed list for
mode primary, which is what
we need to do inserts.
So first thing we can do to
protect ourselves is to catch
the MongoException.
So I'm going to run this with
try / catch, and I'm going to
catch MongoException.
And I'll just print
out the message.
OK, it looks like my 27017 has
reelected itself primary.
So let's run this again.
Now we're inserting
a document.
I'll step down the
primary again.
And notice that I writes
keep failing until
the election occurs.
And now we're inserting
documents again.
And if you look, we started
inserting again at 41, and the
last successful was 6.
So we basically missed document
7 through 40 while
the election was occurring.
So the first thing to note here
is that your application
has to expect exceptions to
occur during things like
failovers or nodes going down
for some other reason.
But you can take action
against it by doing
some sort of retry.
So let's look at one way
to do this with insert.
And insert is actually a very
easy thing to retry because
inserts are item potent.
The sense that if you insert a
document once, inserting again
won't cause any harm.
So what we'll do here is we're
going to put a loop in.
Run this over the loop.
And I'll just say the loop will
be the number of retries.
So I'll say retries = 0, retries
<=2, so we'll do three
retries at most.
retries++ and then I will
break; on success.
And to give the failover a
chance to occur, I'll put a
little longer sleep
in the catch.
So it'll sleep for
five seconds.
But this is not quite right
because in the case where I
have inserted the node
successfully, but I still got
an exception, the second time I
tried to insert it, I could
get a duplicate key exception.
So I'm going to put a second
catch block in here and
specifically catch duplicate
key exception.
And I'll just say "Document
already inserted."
So let's check who my
primary is again.
27017.
So now let's run this.
Answer in my documents
and let's step
down the primary again.
Now we can see [? it ?]
says retrying,
and it's still retrying.
And now we can see it says
primary switching from local
host 017 to 019.
and now we're inserting
again--
10, 11, 12.
And notice in this case,
we didn't skip any.
We have 9 and then 10.
So we didn't miss any
of our inserts.
So how does this
actually work?
Well, what's happening is that
when you use a seed list to
create your Mongo clients, the
Mongo client-- it simply
starts a background thread which
monitors the status of
your replica set.
And essentially, that thread is
pinging all of the nodes in
your seed list and any other
nodes that it discovers from
that seed list, determine which
node is the primary and
which are the secondaries.
So you can see some of these
warnings here are from this
background thread like saying,
warning-- server seen down.
27017.
when we step down 27017, it
broke the connection so it
threw an IO exception here.
And then it also tells you when
we switched primaries--
27017 to 27019.
And that's when the retries
stopped, and the document
insertion began again.
OK, so let's do a quiz.
So if you use a Mongo client
constructor that takes a seed
list of replicas set members,
are guaranteed to avoid
application exceptions during
a primary failover?