Now that we've learned about
replica sets and we've seen
how to connect to a replica
set from the Java driver,
let's back up and talk a little
bit about the anatomy
of a write operation when
you're connected
to a replica set.
So this picture shows a client
application that's connected
to the primary of replica set.
It's also connected to the
secondary, so we'll draw some
lines there as well.
But the writes go
to the primary.
So this is showing a client
application setting, an insert
message, to the primary.
So what happens when
it gets there?
Well, the primary will take the
insert message and it will
figure out what changes need
to be made and write those
changes into RAM.
Specifically, the memory map
files representing the files
in the data directory.
So it'll write it two places--
there, and also to the
operation log, called the
oplog, which is the
secondaries are replicating
off of.
So that's the first
thing it does.
It writes them to RAM.
And then at that point, there
is an asynchronous process
where the writes into
RAM are journaled.
So the written to
the write-ahead
log, called the journal.
And separately, they're written
to the data directory.
So the memory map files
are fsynced
into the data directory.
Both of these give us
durability, but the journal
gives us recoverability in
the case of a crash.
So writes are done to the
journal first, then to the
data directory.
At the same time, the
secondaries are replicating
off of the primary from
the oplog and
applying the writes--
in this case, an insert--
the same with the
primary does.
Into RAM first and then to its
own oplog, to the journal, and
to its own data directory.
That will happen on
both secondaries.
So how does the client
application actually determine
whether the write succeeded
or not?
Well, it's not as simple as
it might appear at first.
So the way this works in MongoDB
is that the insert
message that's sent from the
client application does not
expect a response.
So the client application, if
you were just writing directly
to the wire protocol, you'd send
the insert message and
there'd be no response
from the server.
If you want to know whether
your write succeeded, the
client application has
to send an additional
command to the server.
And that command is called
getLastError, which we
typically shorten to gle.
And it's a separate message that
we send to the server.
And the getLastError message,
it allows the client
application to determine the
durability of the write before
getting acknowledgement back.
So what does that mean?
Well, you have a bunch
of options.
So by default, getLastError will
wait for acknowledgement
from the primary to
write into RAM.
And that is called w=1.
So it's waiting for the single
server-- in this case the
primary, of course, since we're
writing to the primary--
to complete its write to RAM.
We'll come back to
w in a minute.
The next is j.
j basically means that the write
won't be acknowledged.
In other words, the gle command
won't return until the
insert was written to RAM but
also written to the journal.
The third is fsync.
And what this means is that the
getLastError command wont
return until the insert has been
written to RAM and also
synced to the data directory.
So that covers all the options
for the primary, for
durability on the primary.
But in some applications, you
want to make sure that your
write is not only durable
on the primary, but also
replicated to one or
more secondaries.
You use this by changing
the w parameters.
So w can be a number, any number
which corresponding to
the number of servers in your
replica set that the write
should be replicated to before
it's acknowledged.
So let's say I want the client
application for this insert to
wait for both the primary and
one of the secondaries to save
this insert into RAM.
You do that by changing
w to 2.
And then the final parameter
you can use is wtimeout.
By default, say you set w=2
for your getLastError.
Well, the timeout is infinite.
So the getLastError command will
not return until at least
one of the secondaries
acknowledges the write.
But you can set wtimeout to
indicate how long you're
willing to wait.
That is a millisecond value.
So if you wanted to wait
for one second, you
could set that to 1,000.
So let's see how this looks in
Java, how you actually send a
getLastError command in
a Java application.
So here is a basic application
connected to a Mongo client
with our seed list,
three nodes.
I get a database,
a collection.
I drop the collection
and I do a write.
So by default, in the Java
driver and all of our other
drivers, the default
is w=1 and timeout
of 0, which is infinite.
So by default, this write
will be acknowledged.
And we can see that by doing
the write again.
So if I do the insert again, if
we run this, we'll see that
the second insert fails due to
a duplicate key error, which
is what we'd expect.
So if we want to be explicit
about this--
actually, let's say we want
journaled writes.
How do we specify that
in the driver?
Well, it turns out there's
a number of ways.
You can do it at the
very top level.
So if I want all my writes to
default to journaled, I can
set it at the Mongo
client level.
And the way I do that is by
calling this setWriteConcern
method and pass it
WriteConcern.JOURNALED, which
is a constant.
And if we look at what that
constant is, it's just the new
WriteConcern, 1,
0, false, true.
If we look at what those
parameters are, we see the 1
is w, timeout is 0, fsync
is false, and j is true.
And there's a number
of constants that
we'll see in a moment.
So I can set it at
the client level.
That will be the default
for all users
of this Mongo client.
I can also set it at the DB
level, which means that all
writes to this db will
have a default
WriteConcern of journaled.
I can do it at the collection
level as well.
And finally, I can do
it at the level of
the individual insert.
So there's a number of constants
that you can use.
So if we look at WriteConcern,
you can see that there's
ACKNOWLEDGED, which is the
default, a WriteConcern of 1.
There's JOURNALED.
And then there's something
called REPLICA_ACKNOWLEDGED,
which is essentially w=2.
And then there's also--
there's a number these which are
deprecated, you can see,
because we've changed the names
recently to standardize
them across all the drivers.
There's also MAJORITY, which
means that the write needs to
be acknowledged by a majority
of the members
of the replica set.
And finally, there's a funny
one, which is UNACKNOWLEDGED.
UNACKNOWLEDGED basically
means, don't send a
getLastError at all.
And you might wonder why
you'd ever do that.
And the reason is because there
are some obligations
that are willing to sacrifice
durability
for really fast writes.
So if you look back to our
picture, if you're just
sending a lot of inserts and you
don't ever send a gle, a
getLastError command, the
write's going to be really
fast, because I don't
have to wait for a
response from the server.
Once you send a getLastError,
you have to wait for a round
trip to occur.
So there are certain
applications where it makes
sense to use unacknowledged
writes.
And you can see how that
would work here.
If I change this one to
UNACKNOWLEDGED, what we should
see is we're not going
to get an exception.
And the reason is because if we
look back at our picture,
the second time we sent the
insert, we didn't wait for an
acknowledgement.
Therefore, there's no way for
the client application to know
that there was a duplicate
key exception.
The duplicate key exceptions is
actually contained in the
gle response stalk.
So since we didn't send a
getLastError command, we're
not going to get
that response.
And therefore, the client
application is not notified
that there was a duplicate
key exception and
that the write failed.
So let's go to a quiz.
What are the w and j settings
required to guarantee that and
insert, update, or delete--
so any write operation--
has been persisted to disk?
Is it w=0, j=0?
By the way, w=0 is a shorthand
for saying that getLastError
command is not sent at all.
w=1, j=1?
w=2, j=0?