Let's go over how to
provide hints to
MongoDB from within Java.
We're going to use the
same collection.
And I've added some indexes.
So let's look at the
indexes I've added.
I have an index on "a"--
you can see that here--
an index on "b," an index on
"c," and an index on "d," and
an index on "a,"
ascending, "b,"
descending, "c," ascending.
How would we tell
MongoDB to use a
particular index from Java?
I've written a small program to
illustrate how this works.
Let's go through it,
line by line.
First we connect to MongoDB
using Mongo Client.
And after that, we connect
to the test database.
And then we're going to set up
a query where we're going to
look for "a" being 40,000,
"b" being 40,000,
and "c" being 40,000.
And now there's two alternative
ways to get hints
within MongoDB.
One of them is to append hint
onto the query, and specify
the string of the index name,
which you could deduce.
Or you could look for it
by doing a getIndexes.
And then I add explain so that
we get a document back that is
the output of explain.
And then down here, I just
go through that document.
I get its key set.
And then I just print
it out line by line.
It's sort of a poor man's
pretty print.
So if I run that, let's
see what I get.
All right.
And you can see that the bottom
here, a little hard to
read, but it's using the
index a_b_-1_c_1,
the same one I specified.
So that's one way to do it.
And the alternative way to do
it, is to build it up using a
basic DB object.
It looks a lot like a
query in that case.
So what we've done here
is I'm creating
something called myHint.
And then I've created a basic
DB object with the first key
value pair being "a,1".
The second one appended on being
"b, -1," and the third
being "c,1." And then I can call
"find" with that query.
And that hint, my hint, and
it will do the same thing.
I'll show you that.
And you can see that it's using
the same index again,
right here.
Now, it's interesting because
you do need to send in an
ordered pair for a hint, A-B-C.
And these basic DB
objects are ordered, even though
a straight map might
not be ordered within Java.
But this basic DB object
has an order to it.
And it retains the ordinal
values of the different keys.
And so it works as a way
to send in a hint.