So to round out your knowledge
of retrieving data from using
the Java driver, I want to
show you a collection of
documents where the documents
have some internal structure,
and then how you can query into
that internal structure
and select into that
internal structure.
So in this example, we have a
collection of lines, and we
insert 10 lines.
Just to keep the ID simple, I'm
using the value of I for
the ID, which will be unique.
I create two sub-documents
from my document.
One is called Start, and
the other is End.
And each one represents
a point, basically.
And each point has x and
y-coordinates with a value
between 10 and 99.
I did that so when I print it
out, the numbers line up.
And then I create
an empty query.
And I do a find and print out
the results, and let's see
what we get, so you can see what
the structure looks like.
We have our ID, and we have
every document has a start
document with x and y, and an
end document with x and y.
So let's say we want to do a
query where we want to limit
the results to all documents
where the x-value of Start is
greater than 50.
And I can do that using dot
notation that you learned
earlier this week
with the shell.
So I can say start.x
greater than 50.
And when I run that, I only have
documents where start of
x is greater than 50.
So that's using dot notation
for queries.
You can also use it for
field selection.
So I can add a field selector
to my query, saying
new basic db object.
And say all we want is the
y-value of start for all
documents where start.x
x is greater than 50.
So I can do that just by saying
start y is true to
include only start.y.
Let's run that.
Now we have start and we
only have the y-value.
X is gone, and so is the
whole end document.
And again, if we don't need the
ID, we can just append id,
false, and ID will
be gone as well.
And notice that when you do
start.y, it's not like you get
a document that says y of 33.
It keeps the structure, so you
still have a start document
with a single value of y.
OK, let's go to a quiz.
In the following code snippet,
what do you think will happen
if there exists in the
collection a document that
matches the query,
but does not have
a key called media.url?
So the code defines a method
called findOneUrlByMediaType.
It takes a collection of videos,
and a media type to
search for.
We create a query for media.type
equals whatever
media type was passed in.
And then the fields that we're
selecting is media.url.
And then we return the results
of findOne for this query and
this projection.
So what will it do?
Will it throw an exception?
Will it return an
empty document?
Will it return a document
containing a single field
containing the document's ID?
Or there's not enough
information to know?