So we're done with querying
from Java for now, and now
we're going to move on
to update and remove.
So the API for update and
remove in Java is pretty
similar to the shell with some
differences in the way
parameters are passed.
But before I show you update and
remove, I want to just go
over the document structure
we'll be
using for this lesson.
So if you look at the top, I've
abstracted some of the
methods just to keep
the code simple.
So I have a method,
createCollection, here which
just creates a Mongo client;
a database that returns a
collection; and then another
method to print the contents
of the collection.
That's just to keep the main
method simple so you can see
more easily.
And then I create my documents
by creating a list of names of
strings then inserting each of
those names as the ID of a
document in the collection.
And then I print it.
So let's run this.
And you can see that indeed I
have five documents in my
collection--
Alice, Bobby, Kathy,
David, and Ethan.
So let's look at update first.
So update, like find, is
a method on collection.
So the method is update.
And you can see it's overloaded,
but we're going to
use the simplest form first,
which is the one that takes a
query and an update operation.
And you'll see later that
there's a few more overloads
for upsert and multi update,
but we won't
deal with those yet.
So let's update the first
document in the collection,
Alice, by creating a query
for a document
with an ID of Alice.
And this is just
a normal query.
So although we learned about
querying using find applies to
the update.
This can be any query
just like find.
So that's the query.
Now let's say what
our update is.
Now, we're going to start with
wholesale replacement, just
like Richard did
with the shell.
And we'll say that we're going
to update this document and
we'll set an age field
to be, say, 24.
And if we run this we should see
that Alice now has an age
field that's 24, which
is what we wanted.
But since this is wholesale
replacement, if we do a second
update and say we change this
to gender of female, then we
would expect that the age field
is going to disappear.
And indeed it does.
We have Alice ID with
gender female.
And it disappears because while
the first update set age
to 24, it's a wholesale
replacement of the documents,
including ID.
You don't have to respecify ID,
although usually you do.
But when we do the second
update, the document we were
giving doesn't include age, so
the age field disappears.
We can change that by using the
second behavior of update
by using the dollar operators
for the second argument update
instead of a BasicDBObject
representing an entire document.
So we can do that by saying
BasicDBObject("$set" where now
we do a $set of gender to F.
So in that case, we won't
overwrite the age field.
And now when we run it, we see
that Alice has both an age
field and a gender field.
OK, so that's the two basic
behaviors of the update method
on DBCollection using the
default values of upsert,
which is false, and multi,
which is also false.
So now let's look at upsert.
So let's now try to update a
document where the ID doesn't
actually exist in
the collection.
So if I update Frank, we run
this, we should not see Frank
in the collection.
We don't because we're
not doing an upsert.
The query ID Frank doesn't
match any documents.
But if we add the upsert
parameter, true for the third
parameter to update, which is
upsert, then we should expect
that a new document will
be created for Frank.
The ID is Frank, gender--
I should change the
gender to male.
Sorry, Frank.
We have a new document
created for Frank
because we did an upsert.
OK, so that's three of
our four behaviors.
Now let's look at the final
one, which is multi.
So let's say, like Richard did
in his example, we want to
update every document in the
collection and add a title
field of Dr. We can do that by
switching the order of these
parameters--
upsert false, multi is true--
and now we should expect that
every document in the
collection will have a new field
called title with the
value Dr. That is the case.
Alice still has her age 24
because I didn't remove that.
OK.
So that's all the behaviors
of update.
Now let's take a quick
look at remove and
then we'll do a quiz.
So if we want to remove
documents in a collection, we
can do that with the
remove method.
And there's a bunch of
overloads, we'll get to that
in a later lesson when we talk
about WriteConcern, but the
remove method takes a single
DBObject that represents a
query of which documents
should be removed.
We just say new BasicDBObject
that matches everything, so
all the documents
will be removed.
We can see they're all gone.
But we can limit this with a
query and say let's only
remove Alice.
If we do that, then we should
see that we now have four
documents--
Bobby, Cathy, David, Ethan--
but Alice is gone.
So what's a little confusing
about update and remove is
that while by default update
only updates a single
document, remove updates
all the documents
that match the criteria.
And there's actually no way in
the Java driver to tell it to
only remove the first
document.
OK, let's go to a quiz.
So in this quiz you actually
have to write some code.
So do be careful and maybe try
it in an editor first before
you give an answer just so you
don't have any syntax errors.
The question is, "In the
following code fragment, what
does the Java expression in
place of xxxx that will set
the field 'examiner' to the
value 'Jones' for the document
with _id of 1," which we're
already selected in the query.
"Please use the $set operator
to do this."
Don't worry about white space.
The white space should be
stripped, but do be careful
about capitalization
and other things.
And since this is just an
expression, you don't need a
semicolon at the end.
Just the expression that you
would put in place here.