Let's talk about the session
management and how the user
interface works inside
the blog.
You don't actually need to
completely understand this to
do the problem this week, but
it's good to have a basic
understanding of it.
So they have MongoDB, and--
here I'll show it as this,
running as a mongod process.
And you have your application.
And your application
is written in Java.
And inside it, it's got
FreeMarker, which is a
templating engine for the views,
which I'll show you,
and then Spark Application
Server.
So initially you're
going to sign up.
And so you're going to do a GET
request, right here, that
is going to result in the page
coming back to you, the
sign-up page, with a bunch
of fields, four fields.
This is the reply
from the GET.
And then you're going to submit
that with a bunch of
information with a post.
And at this point, what's
going to happen is the
application, if it's a valid
sign up, is going to respond
with a redirect to
the welcome page.
Now they'll also be
a cookie set.
And this is an important part
of the process, because the
application server before it
does this redirect and after
it crosses your post of your
sign-up information-- this is
the sign up form.
So when it processes this post,
it's going to write the
users table.
So it's going to write
the users table.
It's also going to write
the sessions table
and start a new session.
And it's going to take a piece
of information from the
sessions collection.
I should really call it a
collection not a table, it
would be more accurate.
And it's going to set that the
cooking in the redirect.
So when your browser does a
GET of the welcome page--
here's the welcome page--
it's going to present
that cookie.
So the redirect generates a GET,
which generates a reply
on this page that's going to
welcome you, individually.
Welcome Andrew.
So how does that work?
Well on that redirect, the
cookie is set, and now your
browser is going to present
that cookie.
And that cookie is going
to be checked.
When the welcome page gets
processed, the database-- the
application, rather, is going
to do a read query to Mongo,
and say oh, do I recognize
that session cookie.
And if I do, who's the user?
And then, show me the
right information.
So all the session management
happens via this cookie, which
rendezvous the information from
request to request with
the user information.
So let me show you specifically
what I mean.
So here's the blog itself.
And you can see it's welcomed
me right now.
And I'm on the welcome page.
This is after I signed up.
I've downloaded a cookie
utility, which you can
download as well, if you want.
And this cookie utility will
show me the cookies the
browser's going to present
to the website.
In this case, you can see that
it's presenting this long
random string starting
with VBL.
And if you look here, in
MongoDB, you can see when we
looked at the sessions table,
here was that same cookie,
right here.
The same piece of information.
So when the web browser
requested the welcome page
with the cookie, then the
application looked up and said
oh, it must be this user,
erlichson, and then it
presented my information.
And it customized the page
accordingly, right here.
So just again, if you go to the
login page, right, what's
going to happen is when I type
in one username and password
here, like erlichson, and if I
type the right one, then there
was just a round trip, where in
response to the post, the
application responded with a
redirect to the welcome page
along with the cookie that
is set properly,
associated with my user.
All right, so now that we
understand the way the session
management works, then I'm going
to go through some of
the way the code is structured,
so you understand
the way it all fits together.