In this problem, we asked you to
remove the lowest homework
score for each student and then
re-calculate and average
for all the students
to figure out who
has the highest average.
Let's start out by looking a
little bit at the collection.
So we can see what's
inside it.
Here I've just done a find
across the entire collection
and [? pretty ?] printed it.
You can see that there's one
document for each assessment.
So for instance for student
ID 4, there's a
quiz with this score.
And then there's another record
for student ID 4 with
the homework.
Now what we're going to do is,
we have the collection.
And we need to first filter
out and look at only the
home-works.
And we're going to do that
with a find command.
And that's going to get
us a set of documents.
And we're going to sort those
documents by student ID--
I'll put the student ID s ID--
and by score.
So that we can iterate
through them.
And what we can do is
when we see 78, 81.
When we see a transition in
student ID, for instance right
at this boundary right here or
this boundary right here, we
know that we need to remove
the next record.
So we're going to remove for
instance this record.
And we're going to remove
this record.
And we'd remove this record.
And so on.
And that's going to be
our basic approach.
We're going to do a filter
looking for only assessment
type of homework.
So that's going to
be our find.
We're going to sort
them by student ID
ascending and score ascending.
And then every single time we
see the student ID change,
we're going to assume we're
looking at the lowest score
for that student, and we're
going to remove that document.
Alright, let's look
at the code.
So we have remove lowest.
First we create a new
Mongo client.
And then we get the student
database and the grades
collection.
Now we're going to create
a sorted list here.
We're going to create a
new basic DB object.
We're going to sort for
student ID, score.
And then right here we're
going to do the find.
So grades dot find.
New basic DB object.
Type homework.
So we're looking for only
the homework grades.
Sorted by our sorted list, which
is also expressed as a
basic DB object, student ID
ascending, score ascending.
Now remember that these basic DB
objects do retain an order
unlike a normal hash map.
So that's why we use them to
express our sort criteria.
Now we're going to go through
the cursor over here.
And we're going to
look at each one.
Then we're going to see if the
student ID has changed from
the previous student ID.
And we have a student ID here.
We've set it to be an object.
We don't really need to worry
about what it is.
And we're going to run it.
And then we're going to see that
every time there's a the
transition, we're going
to remove that entry.
And this is a [INAUDIBLE]
value to make sure that
we get the first one.
So we're going to print out
what we remove over here.
And then we're going to do a
remove, setting the criteria
that we want to remove the one
with an underscore ID equal to
the ID found in the first one
as the student ID changes.
And then over here we're just
saying the student ID equal to
the next student ID
of each record.
Alright, let's run it and
see what happens.
OK.
You can see here, it has removed
a bunch documents.
And now we can find out the
answer by running that
aggregation query, which
I have stored here.
And that aggregation query gives
us the answer, which is
that student ID 124 has
the highest average.
Here is the aggregation
[INAUDIBLE] if
you want to see it.
We're going to handle
aggregation in a later unit.
But if you're curious about it,
this is the aggregation
command that will find the
student with the highest
average once we removed
the lowest
homework for each student.
OK, so that's how that works.