What is MongoDB?
At the highest level, MongoDB
is a non-relational JSON
document store.
We'll pull apart each of
these terms to explain
what MongoDB is.
First, it's non-relational.
And by non-relational, we mean
that doesn't support the
relational algebra that's most
often expressed as SQL.
So for instance, if you're
familiar with Oracle or MySQL
or SQL server, you know that
they support a relational
algebra between the tables.
And MongoDB does not
support that.
And it's a JSON document
store.
And by documents, we're not
talking about Microsoft Word
documents here.
But we're talking about
structured documents expressed
using JSON, which is a
JavaScript Object Notation.
So let's first start with
what these JSON
documents look like.
Here's a JSON document.
A JSON document starts with
an opening brace.
And then it has keys
and values.
So for instance, you might have
a key of firstname, and
put a quote around that.
And my first name is Andrew.
There might be another key
of last name, and my
last name is Erlichson.
And by the way, these are quotes
around these keys and
quotes around these values.
And that's a comma between
these fields.
And that's a colon between
the key and the value.
So here we have a key, and
here we have a value.
And then we might have another
key called hobbies.
And in that we might have
a list of hobbies.
So for me that would be
cycling and golf and
photography.
And you can see here that I've
expressed this as a list.
So these square brackets
indicate a list.
Then we can close that document
right here, the
closing brace.
And this document can be put
directly into MongoDB, into
what we call a collection.
And MongoDB holds collections
of documents.
So this might be a people
collection, for instance.
So we say that it's
a non-relational
JSON document store.
So this is JSON, and this
is a JSON document.
And this is something that you
can put directly into MongoDB.
Now we also say that MongoDB
supports dynamic schema.
And some people say that
it's schema-less.
And what do they mean by that?
So in particular, there could be
a second document that you
put into the database.
For instance, I'll put one here
with first name Jeff and
last name Yemin.
And let's say city of birth--
I don't actually know where he
was born, but I'll just say it
was Boston.
And then I'll leave
out his interests.
So MongoDB supports having
documents in the same
collection that do not exactly
the same schema.
So for instance this first
document has a hobbies key
with an array of hobbies.
And the second document has a
city of birth key which my
document lacks, and it doesn't
have this hobbies array.
And of course, as you all know,
if you're familiar with
relational, in the relational
world, we've got these tables.
And these tables contain columns
like first and last
and maybe city of birth.
But there's no way to store data
in a different dimension
inside a relational database.
So this could hold Andrew, and
it could hold Erlichson.
And it could hold my city of
birth, but it couldn't hold an
array of hobbies.
It could hold an ID,
like a person ID.
And there could be some other
table that held my hobbies and
that would be related to that,
but you couldn't stick the
hobbies into a list inside
the same table.
Now what you may realize is that
the way MongoDB stores
these documents is a lot
closer to the way that
programs are written.
Because often your programs are
object-oriented and they
have these hierarchical objects
where you've got maps,
and in those maps you've got
lists which are equivalent to
arrays, which may have other
maps inside them.
And you can store one
of those objects
directly inside MongoDB.
It can be serialized into these
JSON objects, and within
a database it's actually stored
in something called
BSON, which we'll
get to later.
And you can't do that in
a relational database.
In a relational database, you
have to pull part everything
into its constituent
pieces and put it
into the various tables.
One analogy is that if you
were storing a car in a
relational database, and then
you take it apart when it came
into the shop.
You'd store all the doors
in the doors table.
You'd store all the steering
wheels in the steering wheels
table, and all the engine
in the engines table.
Whereas in MongoDB, you'd store
the entire car often in
one collection where there would
be hierarchy when the
documents expressing what's
inside that object.
Now in creating this database,
what we've done is we've also
removed some features
that you would see
in relational databases.
In particular, if there
are two collections--
let's say one of people and
another one of the cities and
their properties, let's say.
We don't support Joins
between them.
So we don't have Joins.
So there's no way to query
both of these together.
We also don't have
transactions.
And we don't support SQL.
And some people will refer to
this class of database as a no
SQL database, for either it not
supporting SQL or not only
SQL but we support
something else.
But I think that really the
better way to describe MongoDB
is as a document database, and
in particular a JSON document
database, because that's really
what it is at the end
of the day, a database that
stores documents.
OK, so let's have a quiz.
Which of the following
statements
are true about MongoDB?
MongoDB is document-oriented,
MongoDB supports Joins,
MongoDB has dynamic schema,
and MongoDB supports SQL.
Check all that apply.