This is Jeff, and I want to
review the system requirements
for the class before we start
installing other software.
So first, operating systems.
So we test the class on
two operating systems.
We test on OS 10.8.
But early versions of
OS 10 should work.
We just haven't tested
with them all.
And we also test on Windows 7.
Again, earlier and later
versions should work, but we
test on Windows 7.
And if you want to use Linux--
we don't test the class on
Linux, but there's no reason
that it shouldn't work.
All the software
that you need--
Mongo, Maven, Java is all
available on Linux.
So that should work fine.
For the JDK, we require
version 1.6.
And that's what we test with.
We also test with 1.7.
If you want to confirm what
version of the JDK you have,
you can go to a terminal
window and
type java minus version.
Shows that I'm running
1.7.0, which is fine.
And you can also a test
your Java C version.
And again, I'm running 1.7.0.
So that'll work, too.
So make sure that you have a
recent version of OS 10, of
Windows, or of Linux, and you
have either JDK 1.6 or JDK 1.7
installed as well.