The final project for this class
is a web application.
So one of the things we need
to do is get started with a
web application framework that
we'll use for that project.
So there's a lot of web
application frameworks for
Java, going back to the '90s.
So there's a lot
to choose from.
But this is not a web
application course, so what
our goal is for this class is to
just do the simplest things
possible and choose a framework
that has minimal
dependencies and is really
easy to get started.
So after looking at a bunch of
different things, we chose a
framework called Spark.
It's a micro web framework.
And the nice thing about it
is it's just dead simple.
You don't need a web server,
an application server.
It embeds jetty inside of it.
So all you have to do is define
a main method for a
class and invoke Spark.
And it will automatically start
jetty in the background.
And then you have your
web application.
So like with Mongo Java driver,
we have to import it
into our project.
Let's figure out what the Maven
coordinates for Spark are.
So the first thing with Spark
is that it's not actually in
Maven central, so we need to
tell Maven what repository to
download it from.
So I'm going to add a repository
section in my
pom.xml and add the Spark
repository to it.
And then I'm going to
actually add the
dependency, which is here.
So the group idea's Spark.
The artifact is Spark.
And the release is
0.9.9.4-SNAPSHOT.
And we should see that IntelliJ
added the dependency
on Spark as well as some things
that Spark depends on,
which is mostly jetty
and the servlet API.
So now we're ready to write our
first Spark application.
So I'm going to create
a class called
Hello World Spark Style.
And I'm going to say
spark.get(new Route).
So what we're doing here is
we're calling a static method
Spark class.
And we're giving it a route.
And a route is basically
just one thing.
It's a pattern that this
route should match.
So we're saying that this route
will match the slash
pattern, so it's the home page
for this particular web
application.
And you return object, so I'm
just going to return Hello
World Spark.
So when you start this web app,
and you go to the slash
URI, it will call this
handle method.
And whatever is returned from
this handle method will be
turned into the response
to get request.
So let's run it.
The default port for
Spark is 4567.
You can change that, but we'll
just use the default for now.
And I'll go to localhost:4567
slash, and it says Hello World
From Spark.
If we go somewhere else like
slash notfound, it'll 404.
But slash goes to our handler.
So that's pretty much
it for Spark.
You see how easy it is.
Just to review, we've defined
a main method we're calling
static method get on
the Spark class.
And we're defining one route
for the path slash and
returning Hello World
From Spark.
When we start the application,
it starts listing on 4567 and
returns the webpage Hello
World From Spark.