So we've seen Spark, our web
framework, and Freemarket, are
our templating engine.
Let's try now to put
them together.
So I'm going to steal this code
from HelloWorldSparkStyle
and copy it into a
new class called
HelloWorldSparkFreemarkerStyle.
So we have Spark.
Now let's go back to our
Freemarker code and take this
piece, our Freemarker
configuration.
Change that to this class,
although it it won't really
make a difference.
So in my route, I'm going
to take the code from
HelloWorldSparkFreemarkerStyle
and copy it into my route.
Let's clean this up
a little bit.
So I now have my route with my
Freemarker template created
within the route.
It's complaining that the
configuration is not final
because I'm accessing it from
within an inner class.
So I'm going to make
that final.
And it's also complaint not
return anything from the
Handle method, so I'm going to
bring the writer out and just
return writer on the bottom
outside of the try block.
And I'm going to put
a halt in here.
Is telling Spark that
there's a problem.
We should return a 500 error.
So this looks good.
And let's try to run it.
So we'll got to our web browser
and we'll refresh
that, and it says "Hello
Freemarker" now in the web
application.
And let's review.
So in this class,
HelloWorldSparkFreemarkerStyle,
we created our Freemarker
configuration, here.
We defined a route for
the slash, the
route path of our website.
The handle method create
a template for
hello.ftl, which is here.
We also create a string writer
that Freemarker processes the
template into.
We define a map with a name
key, and a value of
Freemarker.
We process the template,
passing the map and the
writer, and we return the
writer at the end.
The system.out.print line
is not relevant.
So I'll just get rid of that.
And that is a basic Spark and
Freemarker-based website.