So in this optional segment,
we're going to go over SPARK
routes in a little
more detail.
Now, for the blog project, we're
going to actually give
you must of the SPARK code.
But just so you understand
what's happening, we wanted to
give you this introduction to
how routes work in SPARK so
that when you look
at the code, you
understand what's happening.
So the anatomy of a
SPARK application.
On the outside, you have your
web server, which is Jetty.
So SPARK has a embedded
Jetty server.
So when you create a route,
Jetty is automatically started
for you in a background
thread.
And inside, you have a SPARK
handler, such that when a
request comes into Jetty,
Jetty forwards it
to the SPARK handler.
And then within the SPARK
handler, you have one or more
routes, for example, get/,
or get/test, and so on.
And when you come to this web
server from a browser, you
make a request, say, to a local
host, that turns into a
get/ to local host, port
80 by default, but
you can change that.
And that request goes to Jetty,
which, in turn, gets
passed to the SPARK route
handler, which, in turn, finds
the correct route, which, in
this case, is the / route.
The handler for that
route is executed
and a response returned.
So let's look at the code.
So here's an application that
I wrote a little while ago.
It's similar to what we had in
our SPARK Hello World, but
with a few more routes.
So we have our main method.
And we have three routes
to find, each
with a method Spark.get.
So we have get here,
get, and get.
And we define our routes.
Are three routes are /, and
/test, and then a funny
looking one here,
/echo/:thing.
We'll get to that in a minute.
But for a request to /, it'll
go to this handler.
For /test, it'll go
to this handler.
And let me show you what
that looks like.
I'm going to start
this program up.
So SPARK is listening
on 4567 by default.
So I'm going to go to
this web page here.
And / goes to Hello World.
/test goes to this
is a test page.
And that's the first two.
Now let's look at a third route,
which is a little bit
more interesting.
So the third route is defined
as /echo/:thing.
Now, whole: thing is a wild
card, in this case.
And this route will match any
path that starts with /echo/
and then has any segment
after that.
So when the request comes in,
SPARK will match this route
for /echo/cat or /dog.
And you can get the value of
this thing variable, or wild
card, by calling request.params,
and then
(":thing:"), in this case,
to match the :thing here.
So let's look at that
in a web browser.
So I'm going to get
rid of this.
And I'm going to
say /echo/cat.
And it echoes cat.
And that happens because
what we return here is
request.params(":thing").
And if I change that to dog,
it will return dog.
So this is just an introduction
to route handling
in SPARK showing how you can
define routes for multiple
paths in your application, and
how you can use wildcarding to
give a little more dynamic
behavior to the routes that
you've defined.
And in the next section, we'll
look at form handling using
routes mapped to post requests
instead of get.