The next topic I want you talk
to you about is a little bit
outside of schema design.
And it's the topic of how
do you store large
files within MongoDB?
These are files that are larger
than 16 megabytes.
So there's a 16 megabyte
document limit within MongoDB.
And if you want to store
something larger than 16
megabytes, you need
a way to do it.
And GridFS is the way you store
these large objects
within MongoDB.
And these objects are sometimes
also called blobs.
Now MongoDB has a facility
called GridFS.
And GridFS will break a large
blob into pieces for you and
store it into some
collections.
So how does it work?
Well, let's say you had a large
file and you want to put
that file into MongoDB.
MongoDB will break it up into
two different collections.
One is a chunks collection.
And in the chunks collection,
it will put one document for
every 16 megabytes of data that
exists within the document.
So it will break it up into 16
megabyte chunks and put it
into the database in
the collection.
And then, there's a
files collection.
And it will put a single
document in a small document
that will describe the documents
that are put into
the chunks collection.
Now, the underscore ID that is
used in this files collection
will be put into this
chunks collection
for each of the chunks.
They will each have a file ID
that corresponds to the
underscore ID for the meta
document a document in the
files collection.
Now, let's look in
the example.
I've got a video file in this
directory, video.mp4.
If we look at this file,
we can see that
it's about 95 megabytes.
And we can open it up, and
you can see it's a
video that can be played.
And what we're going to do is
we're going to write a program
that's going to put it into
MongoDB and then take it right
out of MongoDB.
It's actually going to put it
into this video copy file.
I'll copy it into a file called
video copy which will
be here when we're done.
Right now it's not here.
So let's look at the IDE and
go through the code.
I've written a GridFSTest.
You can see I've created
a new Mongo client.
And then, I just
get my database
which is called course.
And now, I'm going to create a
Java file input stream called
InputStream.
And then, I'm going to create
a new GridFS object.
And this doesn't really create
the GridFS system, it just
gives you an object that
lets you manipulate it.
And then in this case, after I
associate it with the DB and I
also have to give it a name
which is called videos.
And now as we go down, we're
going to open up this video
file, video.mp4.
And there's some exception logic
to make sure that the
file can be found.
And then, we're going to create
a new handle for a new
GridFS object.
And we're going to do this using
this create file method
right here.
Video is a GridFS input file,
and videos is a GridFS object.
So we're taking that GridFS
object that we created up here
and we're going to call
create file on it.
And we're going to give it the
input stream to this file on
disk, this video
that mp4 file.
And then, just because we want
the name to persist inside
MongoDB, we're going to tell it
that it's called video.mp4.
Because otherwise MongoDB would
have no idea what file
was originally associated
with this input stream.
Now, GridFS has a facility to
let you put other metadata
inside the object as well.
So we're going to do that.
What I've done is I've created a
new basic db object, and I'm
going to have a description,
which is Jennifer singing.
And then, I created an array
list here of tags.
I'm adding some tags to
it, singing an opera.
And I'm going to pen that
to the metadata as well.
And then, I'm going to set the
metadata on my video object.
This is the GridFS input
file object.
And then, I'm going
to save it.
And that's going to save
it to the collection.
And after that, just for grins,
I'm going to print out
the object ID that was assigned
to the document in
the files collection.
Then I just say that
I saved it.
And now, I'm going to
read it back out.
So how do I read it back out?
Well, I created a new
type of object
called a GridFS DB file.
You'll notice this is actually
a different type of object
than I used to input them.
So it was a GridFS input file
when I wanted to put something
into MongoDB, but it is a GridFS
DB file when I take
something out of MongoDB.
And I'm going to
do a Find one.
And I'm going to find the
file named video.mp4.
And I'm able to do that because
I actually stuck that
information into it over here
when I associated this file
name with this GridFS object.
And after I do my Find one, I'm
just going to open up an
output stream with a name
called videocopy.mp4.
And then, I'm going to tell
GridFS to write it out to the
output stream onto disk.
And that's the whole program.
So let's run that and
see what happens.
You see that it ran, it has an
object ID starting on 513, it
saves it back out.
Let's look in the directory,
see what we find.
So now we see there's
a video copy.
And if we open videocopy.mp4,
I'll bring this over to show
you, but there it is it's the
same video as before.
So it seems to be intact.
Now, let's look at what happened
within MongoDB.
So we are in the course
database.
So use course, and we're going
to show collections.
And now, we see there are two
new collections in here,
chunks and files.
Let's look at the files
collection, db.videos.files.
There's actually one object
inside there, it's the
metadata describing
this video file.
You can see that the video.mp4
file name has persisted,
because I associated it with
the GridFS object.
There's an upload time.
And the metadata that I
put in is right here.
So the description, Jennifer
singing, and the two tags are
sitting here in the metadata
collection.
And I could query on this files
collection using that
metadata if I wanted to find
this object again versus using
the file name which
is what I used.
Now there's the object
ID, 513.
So let's look at this other
collection which is the chunks
collection and see what
we see there.
And we're going to see a
whole bunch of stuff.
I'm going to print
it out again.
But this time, I'm going to
suppress printing out the
actual data field to make it a
little bit easier to read.
And I'm going to print
it out pretty.
And you can see that I've got
19 chunks for this object.
I'm not sure if they start
with zero or not.
Let's see if they
start with zero.
Like all good things in
computer science,
they start with zero.
So yes.
So there are exactly
20 chunks.
And I've suppressed the data
field so it looks like these
are small documents.
But they're actually probably
pretty close to 16 megabytes.
And you can see that the file ID
here is actually the object
ID from the files collection.
And that's how they associate
the different chunks with the
original files collection.
Now, I just want to point out
that there's nothing special
about that file name field
in the files collection.
And if I run the program again,
I will have two chunks
with that file name.
So let me just show you
how that would work.
So I'm going to run it again.
And now, I'm going to go
back to my terminal.
And then, you can see now I have
two documents both with
the same file name.
So it's up to you to keep those
file names unique if
that's the way you want to
search on these GridFS objects
in the future.
But, of course, they have
different object IDs.
And it's these object IDs that
actually tie together the
metadata with the chunks
themselves.
All right, let's do a quiz.
Which of the following
statements
are true about GridFS?
GridFS stores large blobs in a
single collection by breaking
up the file into multiple
pieces.
Each GridFS document is given
a unique file name.
GridFS stores large blobs in
two collections, one for
metadata and one for
the blob chunks.
And GridFS compresses
your file on disk.
All right?
So which one of these is true?
And I know that one of them I
didn't actually give you the
answer to, so you'll have
to guess on that one.
So just do your best.