In this problem, we asked you
to make changes to your blog
so that it can accept
blog posts.
All the work you needed to do is
in the blog post DAO class,
and I'm going to show you the
changes that you need to make.
There were three of them.
The first is that you want to
be able to add posts, so you
had to work in this
add post function.
We gave you some hints.
The permalink was already
created for you and the other
items came in as parameters
in the function.
Now you create a new basic
DBObject, and then you put all
these keys and values
inside it.
You'll see here that the title
is put into the title, the
author is the author,
et cetera.
The permalink is the permalink
created above.
The tags, you could actually
add to this object without
making any changes because tags
already implements the
right interface, so that
basically the object can use
it directly.
And then in the comments part,
you need an empty set of
comments, and so what we've done
here is I've created a
new java util array list, which
is going to an empty
list, and then I added
it as the value
for this key comments.
And then for the date part,
I just used today's date.
And I do an insert right here.
I do it in a try, catch block
to make sure that there's no
error, and I return
the permalink.
Now you also need to retrieve
the post in
two different places.
The first is for
the blog index.
The number of posts you want
to retrieve comes in as a
limit, which is a parameter,
so we're just going to do a
find and we're going to
sort by this date.
And you can see the way that
works is you need to create a
basic DBObject and append the
name date, so that it knows
which key you are sorting by
with a value of minus 1 for
descending, and then you can
just call limit on it.
Limit is the number that
came in as a perimeter.
It's usually set to 10,
and the caller.
You can see I've created a list
of DBObjects right here,
and I do the find, and then I
can convert the entire results
of the find, the cursor, to an
array in one call using this
to array, call.
Then I put it in posts, and I
return it, and I close the
cursor on finally.
Now the next and last part is
that when you're on the blog
entry page, that is retrieved by
permalink, you're going to
need to pick up just the one
post out of the database that
corresponds to a particular
permalink.
You can see we've done that
here, created a new basic
DBObject to specify our
criteria with the key
permalink set to permalink,
which came
in inside this parameter.
And then I just set that equal
to post, and return post.
This works very naturally.
If it returned nothing, it would
return null, and so that
works just fine.