In this problem, you were asked
to change the code to
support adding a comment
to a post.
Again, you're going to be
working in the blog post DAO
class, and you only needed to
work on the code that adds the
comment because the comments are
already going to come out
of the posts automatically
in the retrieval code.
And the template will
pick them out.
And so you didn't need to make
any other changes to make sure
that you pulled them when you
pulled the document out, which
is a nice side effect of the
way this document oriented
database works.
So we gave you some hints,
again, that the email is
optional, but it could
come in as NULL.
Basically, we're going to create
a new comment, which is
the basic DB object.
It has an author, which is the
name that comes in here so
name is author.
You had to figure that out.
The body is the body.
Email, a little tricky.
You needed to make sure
it wasn't NULL and
that it wasn't blank.
And if it wasn't either
of those two things,
you'd append it.
The validation script doesn't
use the email parameter, so
this will come in as NULL.
And if you didn't protect
this, you
could get an exception.
And then, this is probably the
trickiest part right here.
You need to call the
update command.
The criteria is this permalink
that came in, so you're only
going to update the document
with that permalink.
But you had to use this push
command to push this comment
object that you've created on to
the array of comments, the
list of comments, inside
the document
with this push command.
And then, upsert false,
multifalse.
So that's how you do it, and
that will push this one
comment on to the list of
comments inside this
particular blog post.